Now that you've seen how neural networks can tackle
more difficult datasets like this one,
let's see how a deep neural network,
many layers, performs on your MNIST dataset from before.
We've got the same objectives that we had prior,
but this time we've got a little bit more of a complex model,
your deep neural network.
You'll see that when you're creating the layers of your neural network,
in specifying your activation function in your code,
the overall process will be similar to what you did before.
You import the training dataset of MNIST handwritten images,
then reshape and preprosses the image data,
set up your neural network model with those 10 classes,
then define and create your EstimatorSpec and TensorFlow to create your custom estimator,
then you're going to define and run your train and evaluate
function to train against your input dataset,
and ultimately evaluate your neural network models performance on the dataset.
Give it a try and come back,
and we'll compare performance.