In this section, we'll review some
practical considerations for serving.
First, we'll build an app on AppEngine
that will make calls to a model serving in
Cloud ML Engine.
And then we'll talk about how your
system architecture can use Apache
to become a full-fledged API.
So let's start with the lab.
In the lab, we're going to create an
AppEngine app that will make rest calls to
our model living in Cloud ML Engine.
And this is similar to the architecture
that you're likely to use for
your applications.
So what's App Engine?
App Engine is a service for
building scalable web and
mobile backends in any language
on Google's infrastructure.
Google App Engine is a fully managed
platform that completely abstracts away
any infrastructure, so
you can focus on your code.
Out of the box, it supports Node.js,
Java, Ruby, C#, Go, Python and
PHP, and it's also open.
You can supply your own Docker image or
bring your own custom software stack
from language run times, to frameworks,
to third party libraries.
Although it's a fully managed developer
experience, you can also drop down into
the infrastructure for
high control when you need it.
Our web application uses Flask, which is
a lightweight framework for developing and
deploying web apps and Python.
In this case, our Flask app is a web form
that takes the features of our model, and
will show the predicted weight.
And this is the interface
that you'll build.
To start the lab, use the provided
script to see what's missing in
the skeleton code, and look for to do's.
After you fixed all the to do's
in the application directory,
you can run the deployapp.sh script
to deploy your app to App Engine.
And then finally, visit your live web app.