Hi, I'm Evan, a technical curriculum
developer for Google Cloud.
In this module,
we're going to put together all the pieces
to build a smart end-to-end work flow for
your newly built WALS recommendation
model for news articles.
In this module, we'll review the overall
architecture of a recommendation system.
Although the content for
your own recommendation system may be
different than what you practice in these
labs, your architecture is likely
to look something similar.
Speaking of architecture, the glue that
we're going to use to bring all of our
refresh data and ML pieces together will
be a Cloud Composer orchestration layer.
Cloud composer is a fully managed Apache
Airflow instance, which is an open source
tool for orchestrating complex workflows
and data processing pipelines.
Our first goal once we have
the work flow environment set up,
is to address the challenge of getting
new data into our ML training data cell.
You'll see how we'll approach this from
a periodic data pull job for BigQuery
running at a set interval to more advanced
event-triggered workflow, like updating
a BigQuery dataset whenever a new CSV
file is loaded into Google Cloud Storage.
Once the data's refreshed,
we need to then periodically retrain and
redeploy our recommendation model and
serve it via an API endpoint.
The two primary pieces of GCP we'll
use here will be Cloud ML Engine,
where we'll submit training jobs to,
and App Engine where we'll deploy and
redeploy our recommendation models for
serving.
Lastly, you'll practice this all
yourself using the same news article
data source and WALS recommendation
model you previously built and
TensorFlow as part of this course.
Recall that you previously built the ML
model that recommends news articles
on the Kurier website.
You saw different methods for
building recommendation models
using collaborative filtering and
deep neural networks.
You then deployed those models for
serving, and
hopefully were pretty impressed with the
recommendations the models predicted for
news articles for your users.
But here's the challenge.
What about when new news articles come in?
Our ML model needs to keep up to
date with fresh recommendations.
Imagine if YouTube didn't show you
the latest videos from a creator that you
really liked or
similar content that was just released?
Your ML model might have been great
when it was first deployed, but
now your recommendations are stale.
And you noticed few users coming
back to your site again and again.
So let's address the problem
of fresh recommendations.
We need to periodically refresh our data,
retrain our model, and then redeploy it.
And we need a smart way
to do this automatically.
Here's an added challenge.
How much should you trust
the pipeline of your upstream data?
In this case, it's new news articles.
Say on Monday,
it provides us with 10,000 articles or
user behavior interactions
through Google Analytics.
But Tuesday that same upstream data source
gives a zero when we were expecting
many more.
Now that we have a living and breathing
recommendation model that's periodically
retrained, we need to
protect it from bad data.
We'll look at a few cool ways that you
can arm your workflows with health checks
a bit later.
At a high level, this is the architecture
that we're going to build for
an end-to-end recommendation system.
The pieces should all
look pretty familiar.
Data comes in from Google Analytics into
BigQuery, which is exported to GCS for
training as a CSV.
Our TensorFlow code for
the model is run on Cloud ML Engine,
which is deployed to App Engine as an API.
As you might have guessed, the glue that
holds this entire workflow together is
Cloud Composer as an overall
orchestration layer.
And we'll spend lots of time discussing
the inner workings of Cloud Composer and
how you can schedule, call and
send tasks to other GCP services.
The end result for our particular use
case, which is serving up relevant news
articles for visitors visiting our
website, will look something like this.
We can make a simple API request to App
Engine for a particular user and specify
how many articles we want to recommend,
and end up giving those articles back.
Now that you've seen the end state,
next we'll walk through each component of
the architecture in greater detail, so
you know the basics before your first lab.