Let's remind ourselves
what our first goal is.
We need to feed our recommendation model
the freshest data that we have available.
Ideally neither you nor I are sitting
by a computer manually hitting
the refresh button in GCS,
a repeat low job in BigQuery.
That's no fun.
As you saw, Cloud Composer will command
the GCP services that we need to run.
But Cloud Composer is simply
a serverless environment
on which an open source
work flow tool runs.
That work flow tool is
called Apache Airflow.
I feel like between Tensor Flow, Dialog
Flow, Data Flow and Airflow, if you're
going to be working on the ML package,
it's likely to end in something flow.
Anyways, bad joke.
How Airflow works is you write
up an ordered set of tasks
as part of what's called a DAG.
More on that in a minute.
And then you watch as Airflow invokes
those other GCP services like
the BigQuery GCS export job here.
Or a new cloud ML engine training job has
kicked off here or deployment of a newly
retrained or trained model, the app
engine, for serving as the API endpoint.
Just a few of the great features of
these airflow DAGs that you're going to
build are the tolerances for failure,
automatic retrying of failed jobs,
and those data health checks that
I alluded to a little bit earlier
that you can program
directly into your workflow.
Now the heart of any workflow,
and by the way I use workflow,
pipeline and DAG a little bit
interchangeably, is that DAG.
A DAG, or directed acyclic graph,
is a set of tasks and
special operators that allow
you to programmatically and
periodically schedule
cool stuff to happen.
Directed means that there's
a specified dependency flow.
First do this task,
then task B, then task C.
And acyclic means it can't be a feedback
loop into itself like a circle.
Acyclic means non circular.
The stuff that's happening in this
particular DAG are four tasks that
update our training data, export it,
retrain our model and then redeploy it.
I'm purposely being ambiguous
by using the word stuff.
Because you can tell your DAG to pretty
much do anything that you need it to do.
Here it's sending tasks to a Big Query,
GCS, and Cloud MLM engine.
But another DAG could send email
notification when it launches a cloud
dataflow job, or
spin up a Google Kubernetes cluster,
or run multiple ad hoc queries
against a Big Query data set.
And you could even trigger
a completely separate DAG
based on the results of the first
one running and completing.
Before we go too far into
Cloud Composer specifics,
I wanted to share this useful analogy.
Cloud Composer is to Apache Airflow
as Cloud Machine Learning Engine
is to TensorFlow.
Both cloud composer and
CMLU are serverless and
fully managed integration layers
to the Google Cloud Platform.
So, you don't have to worry about
what hardware expects your Airflow or
TensorFlow code is running on.
Building any workflow in Cloud Composer
consists of these four steps and
building an ML workflow for
recommendation engine is no different.
We'll start by previewing the actual
Cloud Composer environment.
Once you use the command line or GCP web
UI to launch a Cloud Composer instance,
you'll be met with a screen like this.
Keep in mind that you can have multiple
Cloud Composer environments and
within each environment, you can have
a separate Apache Airflow instance
that can have zero to
many DAGs inside of it.
An important note here is that
sometimes you'll be required to
edit environmental variables for
your workflows, like specifying
your specific GCP project account.
Normally, you would not do that at the
cloud composer level, but instead, do it
at the actual Apache Airflow level, which
is what we'll show you in the next demo.
Again, generally I'm only on
the Cloud Composer page here to create new
environments before I launch directly
into the Apache Airflow webserver.
To access the Airflow admin UI where
you can monitor and interact with your
workflows, you'll click on the link
underneath the Airflow webserver.
The second box you see
here is the DAGs folder
which is where the code of your
actual workflows will be stored.
The DAGs folder for each airflow
instance is simply a GCS bucket that's
automatically created for you when you
launch your cloud composer instance.
Here's where you're going to upload your
DAG files, which you're going to write in
Python, and bring your first workflow
to life visually inside of Airflow.
Let's take a quick look at
a demo of what the simplest DAG
looks like inside of the Airflow UI.
So now I get to see what
Cloud Composer looks like.
And we'll run a very simple DAG that's
going to do a little bit of a work for
us inside of GCP.
So, this is the Cloud Composer
environment.
How you actually get here is
through the Navigation menu.
All the way at the bottom.
You're already familiar with
all the big data products.
Maybe Cloud Composer is new to you.
And you can see the little icon there is
just putting all the pieces together.
I thought for a while, like what
is the T suppose to represent, but
it's a different puzzle pieces.
That'll take you here.
In your lab, you're not going to have
any of these managed Apaches Airflow
environments created yet.
So the first thing as you'd imagine
you want to do is go to Create.
And of course there's a corresponding
shell command line you can actually run
using the CLI to actually create this,
but you can use the UI as well.
So here we just give
the Composer environment a name.
You can specify the number of nodes,
again this is all running
Kubernetes behind the scenes.
Mandatory that you specify a location.
You want closest to you,
optionally a zone.
And I leave the rest of
the infrastructure blank here.
Now you can specify environmental
variables or other labels.
I also leave those the default values.
Now the big, aha moment is currently,
at the time of this
recording each Composer instance takes
about 10 or 15 minutes to spin up.
Here is where you can look
through the rest of the lab,
the rest of the documentation,
that's why I have a few of these other
environments available for us to demo in.
So I am actually going to look at the demo
Composer environment I created a little
bit earlier.
As you saw before,
you've got the actual web server
to take you into the Airflow UI.
You've got the folder to the DAGs.
So the first thing that we want to do
is actually take a look at the DAGs.
Which again, is just a GCS bucket,
there's no objects in there already.
And the DAG, what we're actually going to
be creating is part of our workflow today,
is just going to be a BigQuery related DAG
for the top 100 Stack Overflow posts for
a certain time period.
And that's actually just an example
I took from the documentation for
a cloud data flow.
So here, you can see it's
just a simple bq notify.py.
And it is actually this one is set up to
send an email summary based on the results
of the BigQuery query showing what's
the most popular Stack Overflow post.
So we have our bucket,
again this is auto-generated GCS bucket,
uploading the files.
I've got samples_dag.py.
Once that's uploaded,
we head back into our environment.
You can click on the web server or
click on the actual name.
If you click on the name,
it will give you a little bit more of
the metadata about the environment.
So, you can see this is
the Cloud Composer's name, demo-composer.
And you can see that here is
the actual GKE cluster ID.
But the two links that were also on
the previous page that are really,
really important is
the link to the GCS bucket,
where we can start uploading
those Python DAG files.
And we'll go into much more great detail
on how to create those DAG files.
But the one you want to really
bookmark is the Airflow web UI.
And after we authenticate, you'll
see it's thinking, and maybe refresh
a few times and it will realize that hey,
there's DAGs inside of the DAG folder.
Now, here's the interesting part, as I
mentioned before, you might be putting
environmental variables that
are referenced by your code.
For example, this says sample_dag.py is
expecting something called a gcs_bucket.
And it's essentially a parameter for
whatever you're gcs_bucket is going to be.
So in order to satisfy this and
get the DAG to show up,
we're going to go to Admin > Variables.
And here's where you can create
environmental variables,
that can be referenced by one or
all of your DAG's.
Here we specify gcs_bucket.
I'm going to go ahead and
just create a very simple one.
Create a new bucket.
Call this one just something unique.
Create the bucket.
Bucket's created.
Now we go back in here, specify that.
Now it's vital to understand
depending upon, this is again,
this is a variable name.
Depending upon your code, sometimes
you're going to have to put the gs
google storage slash slash there.
But I just know offhand that
this one already cacatonates in
that as part of the dag.
So, I'm going to leave that alone.
And we're going to save that.
And we're going to see what other
environmental variables are required by
going to dags.
And then we have another one that
says e-mail does not exists,
maybe this is the e-mail that
has sent in the summary to.
So, we again and go to Admin > Variables,
create, e-mail and
then we can just do whatever
your e-mail is when you're
actually creating e-mails.
And I'll tell you why I'm just doing
a bogus email when we get into
actually running the DAG.
Now let's go back in the DAG,
see if there's any other parameters.
We need the GCS bucket.
Our project, GCS project, of course,
we can just get from our home screen.
For your Qwiklabs accounts is going to
be your Qwiklabs projects Id.
And that's where we're actually going to
be running this work low within.
Boom, after all three of those you will
see that your DAG will now appear.
This is the composer_sample_bq_notify.
A couple of different things about
the UI you can plus your DAG
from automatically running.
If you have an automatic scheduler set
up we'll go into the different types of
schedules you can automatically set up.
And then what I do is you
give it about a minute or
30 seconds then when you refresh this,
you'll see the acute notification message.
But then you'll also see all
the links that are available to you.
So you can say this looks like
it's running once a month.
We can take a look, what I'd like to
do is take a look at the code first.
So you can click into the DAG, different
ways of representing it, the graph view.
This is the directed basic graph.
So, you can see that it's
doing a lot of things.
Making a BigQuery dataset, querying it,
exporting the questions that GCS.
E-mailing out the summary while
in tandem it's querying BigQuery,
getting the most popular question queried.
And then reading that out and including
that in the email summary as well.
So that the DAG view here is great.
Also, you can just check
out the code view.
So you can see that at the very
top of this code, it highlights.
Hey, by the way, you're going to
have to specify these three
environmental variables.
So if you wanted to avoid the attack
of the pop up notifications.
You could have just read here and
see that it actually relied on these three
environmental variables
instead of air flow.
This is the DAG, again you can see just
a little bit of what's going on here.
Where it's actually different parts
of the different tasks are running.
This is the actual query, which queries
the public Stack Overflow posts.
Don't worry about too much
of the DAG structure.
I'm going to that in much greater detail.
But this is just essentially a Python file
with a list of dependencies at the end,
for what tasks get run first.
So now if actually wanted to run this,
one of the things we can do is go back
to our DAGs, all the way on the right.
If we don't want to wait for
it to run within 28 days.
We're going to trigger the DAG
with this little icon here.
So trigger it.
Are you sure you want to run it?
Yes, let's go ahead and run it.
And then quickly, what I like to
do is I'll go back into the DAG.
I'll go into the Graph View.
And I'll start refreshing like crazy.
So you want to look for the colored
border in the status or the states.
You're hovering over it and
you see the state in queue.
It doesn't refresh automatically.
So when you're refreshing this,
you can see, immediately,
lighter green means it's running.
So it's making a BigQuery data set.
And if you're following
along very quickly,
I just have BigQuery opened here for
my particular project.
I'm going to refresh that and
see if it actually created it.
Boom, there's the BigQuery
data set it just created.
So we've got no tables in there yet, or
else you'd have a little arrow here.
This is the airflow_bq_notify_dataset
with this suffix of a particular date.
So let's go back, let's refresh this,
let's see where it is now.
So now the BigQuery data set
has been created as we saw.
It's running the bq,
one of those SQL queries that looks for
the recent Stack Overflow posts.
And it's going to be populating those
into two separate tables into BigQuery.
So as you can see that just
finished because again,
it's just a simple call to BigQuery and
BigQuery is going to run it really fast.
Now we're going to go ahead and
refresh BigQuery.
We're going to see how many tables do we
have, actually, in there stored, if any.
Boom, just two queries have ran and
now have results.
The most popular post for
Stack Overflow for
that time period is this article
title with over 340,000 views.
And then here are some
of the recent questions.
As you can see, the most popular
it just takes the top one.
That's what we have our same title here,
and the rest as you can see
in that view count there.
So immediately we have BigQuery data
set that didn't exist before and
we just ran some ad hoc
SQL queries against it.
So let's go back into Airflow and
see what we're doing.
It's export recent questions to GTS, so
it's dumping them to the bucket as well.
And as you can see, we have green,
green, green, green.
Dark green means all of
those nodes have completed.
And then, if you notice, there's a yellow
retry all the way at the end for
the e-mail summary.
So it looks like maybe it failed or
something that's going on with it.
And I'll tell you.
And the reason why I did tests, you might
be thinking that this is failing because
you did an improper e-mail
test at test dot com.
And that's not actually the case.
You can expect these things.
And clicking on a particular node,
I'm clicking on View Log and
you can actually see the error.
So it's saying hey there's no module or
utility named sendgrid or
it's going to give you
an unauthorized email error.
And that's because you
need to actually set up,
in order to send e-mails out of GCP.
This is something new that happened
in the last year to prevent
spam from folks creating these bots.
Is you need to create
an API key with SendGrid,
which is one of the partners that we have.
So unfortunately, we're not going to
be getting any e-mails, which is fine.
The e-mail body would have
just simply been this.
I'll show you.
All the way at the bottom you can see,
hey we analysed Stack Overflow posts
from this date which is parameterized from
this date which and has this view count.
And then the most popular
question was this.
It's pulling this from the GCS bucket,
the file that was dumped into there.
But again if you wanted to actually get
that e-mail, you sign up to SendGrid and
put in the API there as well.
But the big success as you can see is
it it very quickly created this data
set inside of BigQuery, with the two
tables as you see populated there.
So it's got this BigQuery operators going.
And then the cool part is if
we exit out of the code here,
you can go back to the schedule and
you can see.
All right, well every 28 days or
about every month, this
work flow is just going to run, and
it's going to dump in a table inside
a big query with the most popular posts,
and you don't have to do anything else.
It will just run automatically
behind the scenes.
And then, if you put in an e-mail,
if the work flow every fails you can
actually have it send a failure e-mail.
We're going to go through how to
actually create those DAG files.
How do you set up recurring schedule or
an event-triggered schedule.
But all you need to know of the basics of
this so far is just upload a Python file.
Deal with any dependencies for
those environmental variables that'll
give you those notifications.
And then you actually get the name of your
DAG showing up here, one DAG per line.
And then you can interact with it
with some of the quick links here.
All right that's the Cloud Composer
of the very fast demo.
Stay tuned for just much more granularity
for everything that you see here