Now that you're familiar with the basic
environment setup, it's time to discuss
your primary artifact, which is your
DAG and the operators you are using to
call whichever services
you want to send tasks to.
First, Airflow workflows
are written in Python.
You only have one Python file for
each DAG.
For example,
here we have a simple_load_dag.py in our
dag folder inside of our GCS bucket.
And you can see a preview of what
the DAG file looks like here.
Don't worry about reading the code,
we'll go into that later.
It's sufficient enough to know for
now that there are a series of
user created tasks in each DAG file
that invoke predefined operators.
Take for example this task, which
uses the dataflow python operator and
is given the task id of
process-delimited-and-push.
We'll go over creating a DAG file and
its components a little bit later.
Once you've uploaded the python
file to the DAGs folder,
you can then navigate back
to the Airflow web server.
And under DAGs you'll see the DAG
you just created with code visually
represented as a directed graph,
nodes and edges.
You'll remember that the Python code
that defined a task that we called
process-delimited-and-push is
now a node in our graph here.
Let's explore a bit more
of the Airflow web UI.
You can see that this particular workflow
is called GcsToBigQueryTriggered, and
it has three tasks when it runs.
Number one, process-delimited-and-push,
which I just happen to know from that
Python file that you saw earlier.
That this task involves a data flow job to
read in a new CSV file from a GCS bucket,
process it and
write tho output to BigQuery.
Number two, success-move-to-completion,
which then moves the CSV file from
the input GCS bucket to a process or
a completed GCS bucket,
a separate one for archiving.
Or number three,
if the pipeline fails part of the way,
the file is moved to the completion
bucket but tagged as a failure.
This is an example of a DAG
that isn't strictly sequential.
There's a decision made to run one node or
a different node,
based on the outcome of the parent node.
That's how you get a branch.
Now, this is just an example DAG.
More complex DAGs, like the one
that you're going to build for
your recommendation model, will have
more tasks as part of your graph.
Take this new DAG, which has two
BigQuery tasks, one ML engine task, and
one App Engine deployment task.
This is a preview of the last lab,
where you're going to be building
your own recommendation system.
Regardless of the size and shape of
your workflow DAG, one common thread for
all workflows is the common
operators that are used.
If the DAG itself is how to run the code
in the workflow, first do step one.
Then move to step two or step three.
The operator is specifying the what that
actually gets done as part of the task.
In this simple example, we're calling
on the dataflow Python operator and
the general Python operator.
Those are by no means the only operators.
So let's pause here and look at all
the operators that are at your disposal
to achieve our goal of automatic
retraining and deployment of our ML model.
Airflow has many operators,
which you can invoke to use
the tasks that you want to complete.
Operators are usually atomic in a task,
which means that generally,
you only see one operator per one task.
I've taken this list directly from the
Apache Airflow docs of all the services
that Airflow can orchestrate to.
Let's take a look at some of
the ones that are common and
most relevant to us as ML engineers.
As you might have guessed, we'll certainly
will be making use of the BigQuery
operators since our workflows live and
die by the data that's fed into
them through GCS and BigQuery.
Here's a list of the specific operators
that we can invoke in a task to
call on the BigQuery service for
querying and other data related tasks.
You'll be mainly working with
the first three in this course.
But I encourage you to scan the resource
link on all the operators that you could
use, so you can get a feel for
everything that's possible.
Once we have our training
data in a good place,
the next logical step in our workflow is
to then retrain and redeploy our model.
In the same DAG file,
after the BigQuery operator is complete,
we can then make a service call
to a cloud ML engine operator
to kick off a new training job and manage
our model like incrementing the version.
You might have noticed that your Airflow
DAG can have operators that send out
tasks to other cloud providers,
this is great for hybrid workflows.
Where you have components across
multiple cloud platforms or
even a combination of cloud and
on-premise.
Apache Airflow is open source,
and it's continuously adding more
operators to other services.
So be sure to check out the list in
the documentation periodically if
you're waiting for
a new service to be added.