Now, let's examine a specific workflow DAG
that you'll be completing as part of your
end-to-end lab.
Read through the four operators here and
take your best guess at
what this pipeline is achieving in
the short pop-up quiz that'll appear.
Now, let's read through it together.
Here, you see four tasks,
t1, t2, t3, and t4, and
the four operators corresponding to
four Google Cloud Platform services.
The name should look familiar.
You can probably even start to guess
what this workflow does at a high level,
just by reading them in order.
The first two are concerned with getting
fresh model data from the BigQuery data
set and into GCS for consumption by
our ML model later on in the workflow.
In the lab you're going to work on later,
the date set will be one that
you're already familiar with.
It's the Google Analytics
news article sample data set.
Let's see the parameters
the BigQueryOperator takes.
The BigQueryOperator allows
you to specify a SQL query to
run against a BigQuery data set.
In this quick example, we're passing in
a query which returns the top 100 most
popular Stack Overflow posts from
the BigQuery public data set for
a specified date range that you
see there in the WHERE clause.
You notice anything different about
the filters in the WHERE clause?
Yeah, there are parameters in this
case for max date and min date.
You can parameterize pieces of this
SQL statement, like what we did here,
to only return posts for January 2018 with
a min query date and a max query date.
What's really neat is that you can
make the parameters themselves dynamic
instead of the static ones
that are shown here, and
you can have them be based
on the DAG schedule date.
Like macros.ds_add(ds, -7),
which just means this is a week
before the DAG is scheduled to run.
That's what that date
value is going to be.
For workflows, you want to be really
careful with the window of data you use
for training, evaluation, and testing.
What if data two weeks ago was fine, but
last week the upstream pipeline failed and
there were no records returned for
the query?
Zero records returned for
a SQL query is still a valid result,
but you can still imagine
the implications.
You didn't have somehow or someway of
validating the upstream data sources
that you're feeding into your workflow.
This is especially true for recommendation
models, which rely on timely,
fresh training data to make
those good recommendations.
And avoid stale, or even worse, incorrect
or inappropriate recommendations for
your users.
So what can you do to guard our
workflows against upstream data issues?
Two words, health checks.
Running SQL statements on BigQuery is not
only good at giving you correct insights
from clean data, it can also
alert you if something is amiss.
Let's take a look at an example.
There's an operator you can use,
called BigQueryCheckOperator,
which sounds exactly like something
we could use in our workflow.
How it works is, say we had an upstream
data source that tracked the number of
students that went through
training classes cumulated for
all time,
like the one that you're taking now.
This is a data table that logically should
never have zero records passed as part of
our workflow.
So we're expecting
something more like this.
10,000 records or so
are passed into our ML training data set,
and the rest of the workflow handles the
model retraining and deployment as usual.
Let's say for whatever reason or
data anomaly,
the upstream data table was accidentally
offline, or truncated, or moved, and now
it's giving us zero records after we do
a select star into our training data set.
Again, this is still a valid SQL query,
but zero records to train and
retrain our recommendation model
is going to be really, really,
really bad when it comes
to ML model training.
And that's where
the BigQueryCheckOperator can help us out.
If the result of this health check query
returns zero or false, the health check
will fail, and then you can have
the rest of this workflow fail as well.
But even beyond that, you can say you
have a sad path branch of your DAG that
even sends an email alert or
notification for
critical pipeline failures to a human
team for immediate investigation.
I've shown just a sample of,
if the upstream data table zero records,
then fail to work flow.
We can also build a much more complex
logic in SQL using your own health checks
by using something like case statements or
joins against other tables.
And the benefit for you and your team
is that all these checks are written as
part of the DAG in that SQL so they get
and controlled and very highly visible.
Kind of like unit testing for programming.
Now, here's the tricky dilemma.
We saw how easy it is to check for
zero records with a count star and
fail the pipeline.
But what about the case where something
in the data values themselves changed?
We're still getting records passed
through, but they're really different or
strange values.
Take a look at an example.
We have a daily workflow that ingest
the average temperature of the day.
Notice anything funny about October?
That value is way lower than the others.
Now, if you had to make a guess,
what do you think happened?
Barring really strange summer weather
patterns, our upstream data team likely
switched the scale from Fahrenheit to
Celsius somewhere on or about October 1st.
And didn't tell
the downstream engineering or
data science teams who are consuming this
BigQuery table as part of their workflows.
If we use the simple,
does the training data have any records,
this check would have passed and the model
would have been trained, none the wiser.
Instead, we can use
BigQueryIntervalCheckOperator,
which can notice huge changes or
swings in the data distribution, and
then fail the workflow until
further investigation.
This operator checks the values of
metrics, given as SQL expressions,
whether or
not they're within a certain distance or
tolerance of the ones from our parameter
value that you sent, called days back.
Which looks backwards at
your data history for
previous DAG runs to compare it against.
Keep in mind, for
both BigQueryCheckOperator and
BigQueryIntervalCheckOperator,
you can have more than one check
run as a node in your workflow.
A good idea for
machine learning is to set up a check for
each of your key features to test for
null, zero, out of bounds, or
irregular values before they make
their way into your training data set.
And of course, you can always revisit and
update these checks as you engineer more
features, or continue to tune and
train your model.
The next two operators handle retraining
the model by submitting a job to
Cloud Machine Learning Engine, and
then deploying the updated model
to App Engine via an API endpoint.
The ML Engine training operator is
how Cloud Composer interacts with
Cloud Machine Learning Engine, and
thus gives it the ability to periodically
schedule new jobs to be sent to CMLE
as part of your automated workflow.
Take a look through the parameters
you provide to the operator.
First, we specify an ID for
the task we're running and
then the project that
we want to run it on.
For our lab, this will be the same project
that's also managing the Airflow instance
and everything else that
you're working with.
Then you have the option of
creating your own job ID,
which usually involves a concatenated time
stamp or a similar unique identifier.
After that is the path to the actual model
code, which we'll have in a zip file,
which is created by a shell script
after training is run in our lab.
Then the actual Python module
name within your code to
run within the ML Engine training
job after installing the package.
In this example,
we've called it trainer.task.
Next is a series of arguments for
training, which we store into an array,
called training_args.
Those includes the location of the job
directory, where the training files are,
where the output directory is,
and what data we're using.
And the next three, region, scale_tier,
and master_type are GCP infrastructure
parameters where you want your job to
be ran and with what special hardware,
like GPUs or TPUs, if you're using any.
Lastly, once your model is retrained and
ready to be delivered as an API endpoint
for serving, we need to redeploy our
App Engine project with the latest model.
Here, the parameters are simple
since we're just redeploying
our existing App Engine instance
associated with our project.
And that's it, well, almost,
that's the last task.
But at the end of most DAG files, you'll
find is the actual order in which we want
these tasks and operators to be ran.
This is what the D in DAG stands for,
directed.
For example, task two, t2,
won't run until t1 is completed.
This is what gives our graph
dependencies of a workflow.
I can probably guess what
you're thinking at this point.
You could build in some pretty cool
branching of multiple child nodes
per upstream parent, and
absolutely that's totally possible.
Just don't forget to comment your code,
so you know where one branch begins,
where it's going, what tasks are involved,
and where it ends.
As a tip, after you load in your
DAG file into the DAG folder,
you can see the visualization of your DAG
in the Airflow UI as a directed graph,
a Gantt chart, or a list if you wanted.
Reviewing the visual
representation of the order tasks
will help you confirm that your tasks
are ordered in the way that you want them.