By this point, we've got our environment
set up with our DAGs running at
a predefined schedule, or
with triggered events.
The last topic we'll cover before you
practice what you've learned in your labs
is how to monitor and
troubleshoot your cloud functions and
your Airflow workflows.
One of the most common reasons you'll want
to investigate the historical runs of your
DAGs is in the event that your
workflows simply stop working.
Note that you can't have it auto-retry for
a number of attempts,
in case it's a transient bug.
But sometimes you just can't get your
workflow to run at all in the first place.
In the Dag Runs,
you can monitor when your pipelines ran,
and in what state, like success,
running, or failure.
The quickest way to get to this page
is by clicking on the schedule for
any of your DAGs from the main DAGs page.
Here we have five successful runs
over five days for this DAG, so
this one seems to be running just fine.
Now back on the main page for our DAGs,
we see some red, which indicates trouble
with some of our more recent DAG runs.
Speaking of DAG runs, you'll notice the
three circles below, which indicate how
many runs have passed, how many are
currently active, or how many have failed.
It certainly doesn't look good for
268 runs failed and
0 passed for that first DAG.
Let's see what happened,
we'll click on the name of the DAG
to get to the visual representation.
It looks like the first task is
succeeding, judging by the green border,
but the next task,
success-move-to-completion, is failing.
Note that the lighter pink color for the
failure-move-to-completion node beneath
it, means that that node is skipped.
So reading into this a little bit,
the CSV file was correctly processed
by data flow in the first task.
But there's some issue moving this
CSV file to a different GCS bucket
as part of task number two.
Now, to troubleshoot, click on the node of
a particular task, and then click on Logs.
Here you'll find the logs for
that specific Airflow run.
I generally search my browser for the word
error, then start my diagnosis there.
Here, this was a pretty simple error,
where it we was trying to copy a file
from an input bucket to an output bucket,
and the output bucket simply didn't exist,
or is named incorrectly.
Another tool in your toolkit for
diagnosing Airflow failures
is your general GCP logging.
Since Airflow launches other GCP services
through tasks, you can see and filter for
errors for
services in Stackdriver, as you would
debugging any other normal application.
Here I filter for Dataflow step errors, to
troubleshoot why my workflow is failing.
It turns out that I had not changed
the name of the output bucket for
the CSV file.
So after the file is processed
by Dataflow as part of step one,
it dumped the completed file
back into the input bucket.
Which you can begin to see why that's
terrible, because that triggered another
data flow job for processing, and so
on, and so on, and so on, and so on.
As you can see, workflows can be really
powerful tools if we set them up properly,
or really resource intensive,
if not scheduled or architected wisely.
One of the essential steps I
recommend is pretty simple.
Before really scheduling or
triggering your workflow,
try running it manually yourself first.
And ensuring that you can get it to
complete successfully before tying it to
a more aggressive or automated schedule.
There's nothing worst than waking
up to a new workflow that ran for
the past eight hours and
failed each time, and
spammed you team with an email each time
it failed, I've definitely been there.
You might be wondering, if there's an
error with my cloud function, my Airflow
instance would never have been triggered
or issued any Airflow logs at all.
Since, of course, it
was unaware that we were trying to trigger
it if the trigger didn't fire properly.
And you're exactly right if you're
using cloud functions, be sure to check
the normal GCP logs for errors and
warnings in addition to your Airflow logs.
In this example, each time I uploaded
a CVS file to my GCS bucket,
hoping to trigger my cloud function and
then my DAG, I got an error expecting
to find my function triggered that.
Remember way back when I said cloud
functions were case sensitive?
Looking for a function with capital
DAG doesn't exist, if it's looking for
a capital D, lowercase a, and lowercase g.
So be sure to be mindful when setting up
your cloud function for the first time.
You made it to the end of the lectures.
Before I release you to start on the labs,
let's do a quick recap of what we've
covered and
the pitfalls that you can avoid.
Firstly, Cloud Composer is managed Apache
Airflow, and generally all environmental
variables should be edited inside
the Airflow UI, not within Cloud Composer.
DAGs are simply a set of tasks which use
operators to talk to other GCP services.
DAGs are written in Python and are stored
in the auto-created DAGs folder for
each Airflow instance, again,
that's just a GCS bucket.
Workflows can be scheduled at a set
interval, or triggered by an event.
Lastly be sure to monitor your logs in
both airflow and in GCP for warnings and
errors.
Keep in mind, you can set up email
notification nodes as part of your
workflow to alert you and your team
in the event of workflow failures.