In this lab, we'll build a model to
solve the text classification problem
we've been talking about.
All of the lab TODOs are in
the model.py file, in particular,
you will transform text into
a sequence of integers.
Pad sequences to a constant length,
convert a karas model
into a tf estimator, and
instantiate a tf.Estimator.
Finally, you will train and deploy your
model using Cloud Machine Learning Engine.
And feed in new article titles to
the deployed model for prediction,
keep in mind, you have multiple
attempts to start and stop each lab.
So don't worry if you don't
make it through the first time,
we'll review the solution
together in the following video.