We now have a deployed
machine learning web service.
If you send it a JSON request for
the input features,
you will get back a JSON
response with the predictions.
So technically, we are done.
But it's nice to be able to call a web
service from a graphical user interface.
And so this is an optional lab that shows
you how you could build a web application
and invoke the machine learning
model in response to a user request.
This is the architecture.
You build an HTML form,
a web front end with slider bars,
a drop down menu,
a check box and a Submit button.
The Submit button sends
a specified data over to a Python
flask application that's
deployed into App Engine.
App Engine is where Google Cloud
platform started in 2008.
It's a serverless web
application framework.
The web application converts the HTML
form data into the JSON request
that's expected by the deployed
Machine Learning model.
And it sends back the JSON
response back to the front end.
The front end then displays a return
value, 4.48 pounds in this case.
You don't need App Engine to invoke
the machine learning service.
All you need is to be able
to invoke a rest API.
In the next course of this specialization,
we will look at different options
when it comes to production
Machine Learning systems.
And there we will look at how to invoke
the machine learning service from
Cloud Dataflow.
This is a very common design pattern.
You often take historical log data,
transform it using
Apache Beam on Cloud Dataflow as
we did in the baby weight example.
And use that transformed data
as the training data set for
our Machine Learning model.
We stored the training data set
as CSV files on Cloud Storage but
it's also possible to save
the data in BigQuery.
And then in production, in real time,
the logs show up in a Cloud Pub/Sub.
They're transformed the same way
using Apache Beam and Cloud Dataflow.
And then send to the deployed model
on ML Engine for predictions.
This is where dataflow is calling
ML Engine to make the predictions.
And every once in awhile we can take
the fresh data in from BigQuery,
retrain the model,
deployed as a new version,
do an A/B test of the models and
swap the models over.
So we look at this in a lot
more detail in the next course.
But for now, go ahead and
take a look at the last lab.