Welcome back to the lab solution video.
And here we're going to talk
about the much awaited topic,
deep neural networks with dropout for
a little bit more regularization.
So what's the primary driver in neural
network that updates the weights during
training?
If you said back propagation,
that's exactly right.
So back propagation process that minimizes
your loss function, and ultimately gives
better weights and reduces your
loss function for a better result.
But what happens if the neurons in
your network start to memorize or
over fit to that trained dataset?
Like they became too dependent on other
neurons and learn complex relationships
in your training dataset that just
aren't there in the real world?
Well, the example I like to imagine is if
you're back in college during exams and
say you had five people in the class
that stayed up too late, we'll say one,
two, three, four, five.
And they're going to rely on each other,
each different person memorizing
a specific section of the exam,
and somehow without the teacher
knowing they're going to share their
notes or cheat during the examination.
The method works really well if all
five people are present, all neurons,
all those five neurons are here.
And you can just focus on your
section of the exam and memorize.
Now, if you're the teacher and you're
using a method like say, drop out for
your class, for
each exam you get to randomly move or
there is a mute of certain
students from the main room.
Move them to a different room, that's it,
in effect muting the contribution tthat
they have on the overall architecture.
What does that do in our toy example?
Well, if the original group of five only
has two of its original members, and
they only memorize their own sections,
they're likely going to fail the exam,
in our case get a really,
really high loss function.
And the only remedy for the students or
the neurons in this case is to actually
study the exam content more broadly so
that they can think in generalize well
in the absence of say, overlying or
co-adapting to the other
neurons in the network.
That's a dropout in a nutshell.
So the two basic points is the hidden
units of the neurons don't and
they can't over-rely or
co-adapt to other specific neurons.
And it must generalize more broadly,
because you never know which
neurons are going to be there.
So it's a way of creating more sparse
connection in your deep neural network.
And essentially during training time
have a bunch of different smaller neural
networks rather than just
a beastly overall architecture.
So again, this only happens during
training because this is the only time
when we want something like
dropout to prevent over fitting.
It's not as much.
It's not a problem in evaluating and
certainly not our problem in testing or
predicting.
So we need to create a final dropout
layer that targets one of our layers for
dropout with a certain probability, and we
only want that to take effect in training.
So let's take a look at your lab and
see how we can do that.
So again, make sure you clone the repo,
just like you did in the last lab.
And within here we're going back still
into our two different sections of code.
You've got the MNIST models which
is all the way at the top where you
want to change now.
Again, keeping in mind, specify your
project ID, your individual project ID,
your bucket,
if you haven't created one already.
Be sure to create that and
set it to be a regional bucket.
Set in any region you'd like,
I'm using us=central1, it's closest to me.
And now the model_type,
we did dnn in the last lab,
now I'm going to say dnn_dropout for
this lab.
Then you can run each of those here again,
set those different parameters, but
essentially once you do that and
take a look at the model.py file.
This is what we're going to
find our TODOs for today.
So now what we want to do is want to
create a neural network architecture that
uses dropout.
So this architecture we
had before is great.
So let's copy and paste that in here.
And let's talk about where
we're going to apply it.
So what we're going to do,
we want to create a neural
network with dropout on the last
layer with a 10% probability.
Let's address that
probability percent first.
So first thing I want to do is,
I'm going to say the dropout probability,
which we're going to specify
as be hyperparameter.
And the dropout probability here,
Let's say,
Just passes in and we're just going to
say this is going to be a 10% or 0.1.
Now, what does that actually get called
right after that third layer there,
that hidden third layer.
We're going to say the dropout layer and
now the code for
this is just simply another layer.
That's the tf.layers.Dropout.
So much like tf.layers.dense there's
just another layer for dropout,
it's pretty convenient.
tf.layers.dropout, and
you need to specify the target layer.
In this case the input is going to be this
third layer in our network right here,
the line of code immediately
that proceeds it.
Now, what's the rate?
Now, you could hard code the rate,
but since we already specified it,
you could do 0.1 if you wanted to.
That's 10% of the network is going to
be muted of those neurons for
that particular layer.
But we're just going to say it to
the parameter that we created a little bit
earlier just there on line 43.
And now you want it to only
take effect during training.
So basically this is going to
be training true or false and
you actually want to set that based
on the mode that we have here.
And the mode here is going
to be the tf estimator and
let me just bring this in.
And, this is going to be our whether or
not what mode we're currently in.
So it could be a training
evaluation of prediction as well.
And we only actually want drop
out to actually happen as we
mentioned during training.
All right, that's all there is to it,
adding just simple probability parameter,
10%.
You can feel free to adjust that
of your model architecture and
adding in a dropout layer and
saving your model file.
And this is going to be a slightly
modified version of our DNN with dropout.
And it might have a slightly increased
training time as you might see because
with each training run,
you're eliminating or
muting some of those runs in your network.
Here, so you're going to get
a different architecture each time.
And it helps it to be a little
bit more generalizable.
So let's see, so let's run
the code back in the MNIST models.
Making sure that your
model type is dnn dropout.
That's the current one that
we're going to be testing.
And then we can see how well
it does locally with 100
steps, By simply running this.
And, again the reason why we run this
locally is to make sure you don't have
the errors in your code before you
start spinning up our cloud machine
learning engine job.
So just like what we did before from
that runs all the way down here.
We see laws for the final step.
We're calling it the graphs
that's been finalized.
We're going to get it an accuracy again.
We're willing to do 100 steps here and
an accuracy of 91.
So that means our code
it's running at least.
And then what we can
do it's spin it up and
run say 12,000 steps Using a little
bit more powerful hardware.
in this particular case you're going to be
invoking GPUS much like you did in your
last lab.
So when you run that and
we're ACTUALLY going to be using 10,000
steps you can actually start to kick
off you cloud machine or engine job.
I've already done that'll take
you anywhere between 10 and
20 minutes to run depending
upon when you run it.
And when you go into Cloud Machine
Learning Engine all at the bottom you see
artificial intelligence in your
navigation menu click on ML Engine.
You'll see the job that gets
submitted is the training job.
And then this one completed.
It took me about 11 minutes to complete.
Then you can click into it and
view the logs.
And here's where you can get the actual
accuracy over those 10,000 steps, so
what I like to do is just either
type in steps or accuracy.
It'll take me to the last one.
You'll be able to see that.
We have an accuracy of 96 almost 97%.
So if you're wondering what's the point of
dropout if we're getting about the same
accuracy percentages as we did with
the deep neural networks before.
And again it's all point
of generalizeability.
This neural network that comes
out with the dropout layer is,
say you add more training data or
different training data.
It's going to be a little bit more robust
and less rigid and less likely to overfit.
So typically, even with networks
that you're going to see later on,
the convolutional neural networks.
It's a very good idea for
a regularization technique to add
in a dropout layer just to make
your network a little bit more nimble and
less susceptible to overfitting.
So that's 97% there.
And once you've done that,
then we're going to kick off the last bit.
We've done training,
we've done evaluation and
now we need to actually deploy and predict
Here we run the best script that actually
does the Cloud ML Engine model creation.
This is going to be deploying it so we
can actually run a prediction against it.
I changed the code just because I like
having multiple different models.
One for each of the different
model types to be mnist_dropout,
you can leave it as mnist if you want.
Keep in mind if you have a model that
already exists and you try to run this
code, you could get an error that says the
resource and the project already exists.
That's because when you actually head over
to Cloud ML Engine you go into Models,
you could have that model
that already exists.
Now you could replace it if you wanted to
or you can delete it here in the UI and
then just rerun that code.
Once that model deployment is complete.
Normally it take three to four minutes,
then we can actually do some predictions
with our new deep neural
network with dropout.
So again here much like we did in last
lab, you can snag one of the images.
I'll challenge you to try and
find one that's is very, very hard for
even humans and see how the model does.
And here we just chosen image number 115
we'll be changing that to heart's content,
maybe to 9 maybe to 4.
I think it's a 4.
Maybe it'll confuse the model.
It will think that it's a 9.
And run that.
Keep in mind if you change your model
name, be sure to change it here as well.
This is not prioritized.
The model name is just whatever
you put into this value.
And of course,
it picked it up that it was a 4.
And this is the probability.
You can see that 0, 1, 2, 3 are all very,
very small numbers, to the power of -0.08.
And then 98% is going to be the output for
the class of 4.
So that is deep neural networks with
the additional stability of having
a dropout layer, again,
just reviewing that.
The dropout layer that we added
as a probability of 10% here and
you can see that it will only
applies during training.
Just so, there's no point in running it
for evaluations as well as evaluating for
that while loop.
And we're only trying to prevent over
fitting during the training of the model.
All right, additional documentation is
available through the Tensor Flow website,
tf.layers.Dropout.
And that concludes working with
the MNIST data set with a linear deep
neural network,
deep neural networks with dropout.
We've gotten around 97% accurate, again,
on the data set that we were given.
We'll show you how you can get that
additional percentage point or
two of accuracy, and explore a new model
type that actually handles the variations
in images, like if they are rotated ever
so slightly, if there was noise in them.
You can imagine that linear networks and
neural networks might perform not as well,
especially at scale.
That's going to be your
convolutional neural network and
that lecture is coming up next.