In the prior chapters in this course we
focused on creating an end-to-end machine
learning pipeline in GCP.
The task of developing a model could
take the most time in this process.
But what if you wanted to quickly
test some ideas about some of
the features in your model?
And then what happens if you wanted to
quickly test that model out at scale?
That's where BigQuery machine learning,
or BQML, can come in.
And you know that building ML
models can be very time intensive.
You first must export small amounts
of data in from BigQuery into Pandas
and Data Lab.
You then transform that data
to be used for TensorFlow,
and then you build the model in TensorFlow
and then train it locally or on a VM.
Doing that with a small model then
requires you to get more data and create
new features, improve the performance
rinse and repeat all over again.
It is tedious and hard, so you end
up stopping after a few iterations.
With BigQuery ML, you can use SQL for
machine learning.
Let's repeat that point.
No Java, no Python code is needed,
just basic SQL or SQL to
invoke powerful ML models right where your
data already lives, inside of BigQuery.
The BigQuery team hass hidden a lot of
details, like hyperparameter tuning or
common tasks like manual coding
of categorical features from you.
Now, those options are there for
you if you want to use them, but for
simplicity the models are run
just fine with minimal code.
This can be helpful for
quicker model development and for
smaller data science teams who
want to empower their data and
business analysts to build and
run their own ML models.
With BigQuery ML,
you don't need to worry about extract
transform loads, or writing TensorFlow.
If you have an intuition about a set
of features, you can quickly and
easily test and build and
evaluate a machine learning model right
inside of BigQuery using StandardSQL.
This greatly speeds up development,
because you don't have to worry about
data movement and transformation.
All the action happens
right within BigQuery.
You can do all of this from within
the BigQuery UI, however if you like
notebooks like I do, you could also do
it from a Jupyter or Data Lab notebook.
And this is what you'll be
doing inside of your next lab.
BigQuery ML was designed
with simplicity in mind.
To that end, you don't need it to
define things like the learning rate or
even the test or training set.
If you let it,
BigQuery ML will do that for you.
In addition, with the options keyword,
you can set things like regularization,
the strategy for
splitting your training and test sets, and
the learning rate if you
wanted to do it yourself.
So what do you get out of the box?
First, BigQuery ML runs in StandardSQL,
and if you use normal SQL syntax like user
defined functions, subqueries, and joins,
anything you can do inside of SQL, you
can do to create your training datasets.
Now for model types, you can choose from
either linear regression for forecasting,
or classification models using logistic
regression, binary or multiclass.
As part of your model evaluation, you'll
get access to fields like the ROC curve,
also accuracy, precision-recall,
that you simply select from with your
SQL after your model is trained.
You could also inspect
the weights of the model and
perform a feature distribution analysis.
Entire process is going to look like this.
First, you'll need bring in your data in
the BigQuery if it isn't there already.
Here again, you can ernich SQL
data warehouse with other data
sources by using something
like a SQL join, very easy.
Next is feature selection and
preprocessing, which is
similar to what you've been exploring so
far as part of the specialization.
And here's where you can put
all your good SQL skills to
the test in creating a great training
dataset for your model to learn from.
After that, here's the big moment,
this the actual syntax for
creating a machine learning
model inside of BigQuery.
[LAUGH] It's short enough that I can
fit it in just this small box of code.
You simply say, create model,
give it a name, specify mandatory options
like the model type, pass in your SQL
query with your training dataset,
press Run Query and then sit back and
watch your model run.
After your model's trained, you'll see
it as a new dataset object in BigQuery.
It's pretty wild if you
haven't seen it before.
And then you can execute an ml.evaluate
query to evaluate the performance of
your trained model against
your evaluation data set.
Here you can analyze loss metrics like
RMSC or root mean squared error for
forecasting models in the area under
the curve, accuracy, precision, recall for
classification models like
the one that you see here.
When you're happy with the performance
of your model, you can then use it for
predictions with this even shorter query.
Just invoke the ml.predict command
on your newly trained model and
get back both predictions and the model's
confidence in those predictions.
You'll notice a new field in
the results when you run this query.
And that's where you'll see your
labeled field with predicted,
added to the field's name which is your
model's prediction for that label.