Hi, welcome to the fourth course
of the Advanced Machine Learning
on GCP Specialization.
I'm Max, a machine learning curriculum
developer for Google Cloud.
In this course, we'll learn how to
make predictions on sequences of data.
We'll cover common business use cases
like, time series prediction and
how to deal with more recent data
points getting more relevance.
And translating entire sequences
also known as sequences of words
into other languages.
You'll get hands on practice training your
very own sequence models on a variety of
public datasets.
Let's review why modules
are part of this course.
First, you'll learn what a sequence is.
See how you can prepare a sequence data
for modeling and introduce some classical
approaches to sequence modeling,
and practice applying them.
In the next module,
we'll introduce Recurrent Neural Nets,
explain how they address the variable
length sequence problem,
explain how our traditional optimization
procedure applies to RNNs, and
review the limits of what RNNs can and
can't represent.
Then, we'll dive deeper into
different models beyond RNNs.
We'll talk about LSTMs,
deep RNNs, and more.
Next we'll talk about how transfer
learning applies to natural language.
You'll learn how researchers in other
disciplines have historically constructed
embeddings of words without
training on a supervised task.
You'll learn about recent
techniques called GloVe and
word2vec that are inspired
by those techniques.
How you can easily make use of pre-trained
word2vec embeddings using TensorFlow Hub.
And how your task and the amount of data
that you have determine how you should use
word2vec and GloVe in your model.
Lastly, we'll focus on a sequence
to sequence model called
the Encoder-Decoder Network to solve
tasks such as machine translation,
text summarization, and
question answering.