Hi, I'm Laurence and
I'm a developer advocate on Google
brain focused on intensive flow.
In this course, you're going to
be learning the considerations
behind architecting and implementing
production machine learning systems.
Now one key consideration of
this of course is performance.
In this module, you'll learn how to
identify performance considerations from
machine learning modules.
Now machine learning models
are not all identical.
For some models you'll be focused
on improving IO performance and
on others, you'll be focused on
squeezing out more computational speed.
Depending on what you're focus is,
you will need different ML infrastructure.
Whether you decide to scale
out with multiple machines or
scale up on a single machine with a GPO or
TPM.
Sometimes you might even to do both
by using a machine with multiple
accelerators attached to it.
Now it's not just the hardware choice,
the hardware is select also inform your
choice of the distribution strategy.
This is a fast evolving area and
some of the things that we show you
are still are very alpha stage and
evolve contributions from
the tends of low community.