Let's practice implementing transfer learning using Inception,
also known as Google net.
Inception is a model that Google described in 2014
paper that recognizes 1,000 categories of images.
The source model that will draw from has been trained on millions of images,
far more than we have and it will improve on performance
over a model that we could train with the limited data set that we have.
The first part of our Lab consists of a Dataflow pipeline
that does some of the same things we did with our input function,
but ultimately converts the images into TF record files which
the model will read from much faster than our original image files.
Then, we train the model.
Because our data set is small,
we'll freeze the Inception Model.
Check out how much better this model
performs compared to the one that we trained on just our data.