Hi. I'm Lak, and I lead the team that's
putting together this course and this specialization.
In this module, we will look at building hybrid machine learning models.
You will learn how to build hybrid machine learning models
and how to optimize TensorFlow graphs for mobile.
Let's start by discussing a technology called Kubeflow,
which helps us build hybrid cloud machine learning models.
But why are we discussing hybrid in the first place?
Why would you need anything other than Google Cloud?
Google Cloud is a great place to do machine learning.
You have access to ready-made models like the Vision API and Natural Language API, etc.
The key aspect of these models is that they are trained on Google's massive datasets.
Sometimes, though, ready-to-run models like the Vision API don't quite fit,
and in that case,
you might want to train a family of models using
your own images and your own labels to customize and add in the Vision API.
That is called Auto-ML and that is possible only on the Cloud.
But even if you're building custom machine learning models,
you have reason to do machine learning on GCP.
While TensorFlow is open source,
a serverless execution environment like
Cloud ML Engine allows your data scientists to not have to worry about infrastructure.
Plus, of course, the integration with
distributed cloud storage and serverless and BigQuery,
make the overall development experience a lot better than
if you had to provision and manage all that infrastructure yourself.
So far, in this series of courses,
we have assumed that you're in a cloud native environment, and so,
we prototyped and developed our code using Cloud Datalab,
and then once we had the code working on a small sample of data,
we submitted the training job to Cloud ML Engine to operate on the full dataset.
We also served out the model using
Cloud ML Engine so that we didn't have to worry about infrastructure.
There are times, however,
when you cannot be fully cloud native.
What kind of situations?
You may not be able to do machine learning solely on the Cloud.
Perhaps, you are tied to On-Premises Infrastructure,
and your ultimate goal is to move to the public cloud but it's going to take a few years.
Perhaps, there are constraints about being able to move
your training data off your On-Premise cluster or data center.
So, you have to make do with a system that you have.
Or maybe the data that is being produced
is produced by a system that is running on a different cloud.
Or the model predictions need to be consumed by an application on some other cloud.
So, you need a multi-cloud solution,
not a solution that is solely GCP.
Or maybe, you're running machine learning on the edge and
connectivity constraints force you to have to do your predictions on the edge,
on the device itself.
So, you have to do inference on the edge.
This is a very common situation if you're doing Internet of things.
So here, for example,
is Cisco's Hybrid Cloud Architecture.
Cisco partner with Google Cloud to bridge
their private cloud infrastructure and
their existing applications with Google Cloud Platform.
So, notice the use of Google Kubernetes Engine to manage your container deployments.
Kubernetes is a container orchestration system
that was designed and then open-sourced by Google.
So, why Kubernetes?
Using Kubernetes, it is possible to orchestrate containers
whether they are running On-Prem or on the Cloud, any cloud.
So, one possible solution to retain the ability to move fast,
minimize your infrastructure management needs and
still retain the ability to move or burst to GCP,
is to use Kubernetes.
Specifically, a project called Kubeflow
helps you migrate between Cloud and On-Prem environments.
Kubeflow is an open source machine learning stack built on Kubernetes.
On Google Cloud, you can run Kubeflow on Google Kubernetes Engine, GKE.
However, you can run Kubeflow on anything from a phone,
to a laptop, to an On-Prem cluster.
Your code remains the same.
Some of the configuration settings change, but that's it.