Welcome back,
I hope you were able to train and
deploy an article classification model
with reasonably good performance.
While our model performs well, our model's
rest API leaves something to be desired.
Currently, in order to classify articles,
we put the burden of integerizing
the text on the client.
This was necessary, because we were
using Python level functions for
this preprocessing.
Python functions can't be embedded
into a TensorFlow graph and
therefore can't be called from
our serving input function.
This means all of our clients need to know
how to preprocess the text exactly
the same way we did during training.
They need to ignore the same punctuation,
and they need a copy of the same word
to integer mapping that we used.
This also means that every time we
update our word to integer mapping,
we need to provide this new
mapping to all the clients.
This is messy, and invites training
serving skew, which is when
the preprocessing of data during serving
deviates from how it was preprocessed
during training, which confuses
the model and yields poor results.
To solve this,
we need to refacture our preprocessing
code to use native Tensorflow functions.
Once we do this, we can make
the preprocessing functions part of
the serving input function, which
becomes part of the serving graph, and
part of TensorFlow model itself,
thus eliminating training serving skew.
We also make using our
API much simpler for
clients, because they can
pass us article directly,
instead of worrying about how to
preprocess them properly first.
So why didn't we use native
TensorFlow functions to begin with?
Well, TensorFlow is still
a growing framework, and
there are still many tasks that
are easier to do in native Python.
As of now, natural language
preprocessing is one of them.
Doing it in Python is easier, and
if we're not planning to deploy our model
to production, we can get away with it.
However, if we want to make
a robust production ready model,
we should do things with the native
TensorFlow whenever possible.
This trade off between doing things
the easier way in Python and
doing things the more
robust way in TensorFlow
is a trade off you'll likely
face in your own work.
Many times the best way is to start with
Python for rapid prototyping, then convert
it to TensorFlow later, if and
when you need to productionize your code.
You may be thinking,
what about just adding the Python
preprocessing to the server-side?
Just because the preprocessing
isn't done inside the model,
doesn't mean I have to
burden the client with it.
That's a valid point.
Your architecture would be a bit more
clunky, but that's not a deal breaker.
However, what if you don't
want to have a server at all.
Maybe you want to run your model
directly on a mobile phone.
Now, you would have to find a way to
reimplement that logic for mobile.
The real payoff for sticking to native
TensorFlow is that you can write your code
once and deploy it on mobile, on a server,
or even on an embedded device without
having to worry about
platform-specific dependencies.
The actual process of converting
a program to native TensorFlow
consists of identifying
the functions that are native Python
then identifying
the TensorFlow equivalent.
Now this table is an over simplification,
because the TensorFlow functions
usually aren't drop and
replacements for the Python functions.
They usually have slightly different APIs,
and
may require some supporting code around
them to accomplish the same behavior.
To fully appreciate the differences,
let's walk through a version of our text
classification code, which implements
native TensorFlow preprocessing.