So now you've seen how to use TensorFlow Hub to create embeddings
and to assess the quality of those embeddings using a semantic evaluation.
Assuming they met your criteria,
the next step would be incorporating the embeddings into
your model and that's also really easy to do.
The TensorFlow Hub API has two functions; text embedding column,
and image embedding column and these allow you to
easily use the pre-trained models as input to yours.
Here's an example of how to use a text
embedding column as an input to a canned estimator,
in this case DNN classifier.
It's as simple as including it in the feature columns list.
Note how we specify the value of key as "sentence".
This is so that your input function which recall will return a dictionary
mapping keys to tensors will know which input to map to your embedding column.
Note how we've set the trainable parameter.
Setting the trainable parameter to false freezes the pre-trained models parameters.
Unfreezing it is simple as changing it to true, and there you have it.
You've seen how to create embeddings of words with rich semantic properties either from
scratch or from a library of easy to use modules on TensorFlow Hub.
Are you curious to learn more about how to create a character
ad-on like the one that we used to generate Shakespeare?
That's coming up in the next module.