So far,
we have looked at training performance.
Now we'll take a look at performance
when it comes to predictions.
So how do you obtain high
performance inference?
Well, you need to consider several aspect.
There's the throughput requirements,
how many queries per second
do you need to process?
There's latency requirements, that
means how long a query actually takes.
And then there's costs, and
that's in terms of infrastructure and
in terms of maintenance.
There are essentially three
approaches to implementing this.
Using a deployed model, which is REST or
HTTP API for streaming pipelines,
using Cloud ML Engine batch
prediction jobs for batch pipelines.
Or using Cloud Dataflow direct model
prediction, which can be used for
both batch and streaming pipelines.
So let's take a look at the third option,
and we'll delve into it a bit, and
this will help clarify
our terminology as well.
We're using the word batch differently
from the word batch in ML training.
Here we're using batch to
refer to a bounded dataset.
A typical batch data pipeline reads
data from some persistent storage,
either a data lake like Google Cloud
Storage or a data warehouse like BigQuery.
It then does some processing and writes
it out to the same or a different format.
The processing carried
on by Cloud Dataflow
typically enriches the data with
the predictions of an ML model.
Now, there are two options to do this,
either by using a TensorFlow SavedModel
and loading it directly into the dataflow
pipeline from cloud storage.
Or by using TensorFlow Serving and
accessing it via an HTTP endpoint as a
microservice, either from Cloud ML Engine,
as shown, or using Kubeflow,
running on a Kubernetes engine.
So far,
we've used the HTTP endpoint approach.
But for performance reasons,
you might want to consider
the SavedModel approach as well.
So what option gives the best
performance for batch pipelines?
Well, as usual, this depends on
the aspect that's most important to you.
In terms of raw processing speed, you want
to use Cloud ML Engine batch predictions.
The next fastest is to directly load
the SavedModel into your dataflow job and
then invoke it.
The third option, in terms of speed, is to
use TensorFlow Serving on Cloud ML Engine.
But if you want maintainability,
the second and third options reverse.
The batch prediction is still the best.
What's not to love about
a fully managed service?
But using online predictions
as a microservice allows for
easier upgradeability and
dependency management than loading up
the current version into the dataflow job.
This graph is from an upcoming solution,
see https://cloud.google.com/solutions/.
By the time this video is
available on Coursera,
this solution might already
have been published.
A streaming pipeline is similar, except
that the input dataset is not bounded.
So we read it from an unbounded source,
like a pub/sub, and
we process it with dataflow.
You have two options of SavedModel or
TensorFlow Serving here as well,
with TensorFlow Serving
hosted on Cloud ML engine.
For streaming pipelines,
the SavedModel approach is the fastest.
Using mini-batching,
as we recommended earlier in the module on
implementing serving, helps reduce
the gap between the TensorFlow Serving,
HTTP endpoint approach,
supported by Cloud ML Engine, and
directly loading the model
into the client.
However, the Cloud ML Engine
approach is much more maintainable,
especially when the model will be used for
multiple clients.
Another thing to keep in mind is that as
the number of queries per second keeps
increasing, at some points the saved
model approach will become infeasible.
But the Cloud ML Engine approach
should scale indefinitely.