Okay. So, let's go ahead and try out Vision API in this lab.
As you can see, here I'm logged into cloud.google.com/vision,
and this is where I can access the APIs directly from the browser.
As I scroll down further in the page,
notice that there's a box where you can try the API by dragging an image,
and I have already prepared a file that contains a cloud image in it.
So, as you recall,
the problem statement was to check if an image contains a cloud.
In this case, once I've uploaded the file,
the cloud was recognized with 99 percent accuracy.
So, that's great, but this was an easy problem.
Let's make it harder. Now, it's time to try the web browser version of the API yourself.
I'll provide these free images for you,
but feel free to experiment and provide your own.
Head to cloud.google.com/vision.
Try the Vision API,
and then come back to the lesson when you're done.