In this final lab,
you'll fill in the to-dos as part of the DAG,
and the recommendation system notebook.
Here you'll put your knowledge to the test on each task and
operator that's part of the production recommendation system, ML model.
Specifically, you'll review the architecture as a whole,
and diagram the lists of tasks and services needed.
Then you'll set up the workflow environment inside of
Cloud Composer which will provide you a link to the Apache Airflow Web server URL.
Next, you'll modify and complete the DAG file to
automatically send task to BigQuery and Google Cloud Storage,
to refresh the Google Analytics news articles for
consumption later in retraining your recommendation model.
Next, you'll complete the DAG file with submitting
a job to the Cloud Machine Learning Engine to retrain the model,
and then a job to App Engine to redeploy the updated application endpoint.
Finally, you get to test your new application to
serve up article recommendations for users using HTTP request.
Entire app architecture will look like this in the end.
The specific pieces of the DAG that you'll complete,
are the four tasks names shown here.
So, that's it.
Go ahead and get started with the end-to-end recommendation system lab,
and return back here for the solution walkthrough.