We've talked about a lot of considerations about real world data.
Now, it's your turn to practice with this next lab.
In this lab, you'll see how to resample data,
split up sequences, generate a sequence of predictions and more.
You should proceed in the following order.
First, run the notebook as is.
Look at the data visualizations,
then look at the predictions at the end.
Next, play with the RESAMPLE BY and SEQLEN length hyperparameters.
Next, try predicting N data points ahead instead of only one ahead.
Finally, improve your RNN model by adding layers and adding regularization.
This is a longer lab.
So, keep in mind you have multiple attempts to start and stop each lab,
and don't worry if you don't make it through on the first time.
We'll review the solution together in the following video.