Let's take a break from the theory, and
look at how to build RNN models
in practice using TensorFlow.
There are two TensorFlow APIs
that support RNNs.
One is ts.keras, and the other is tf.nn.
In the labs in this
module we will use tf.nn.
But you'll get exposure to tf.keras and
the text classification ad
which is in the next module.
First we choose our cell type,
basic rnn cell,
basicLSTM cell and GRUCell,
correspond to simple RNN,
LSTM and Gru respectively.
We initialize the cell with the cell
size which is a hyperparameter that
specifies the vector size of
the cell's internal state.
We tune this in the same way we
would choose the number of units in
a dense layer.
Too large and the model will be too slow.
Too small and the model may not
have enough learning capacity.
Once we initialize our cell,
we actually unroll our RNN.
The operation for
this is tf.nn.dynamic_rnn and
it takes three arguments.
The RNN cell, which we just instantiated,
a Tensor of features, and a data type.
The feature Tensor state contains
our inputs for all time steps, and
must have the shape, batch size, time
sequence length, times input dimension.
Input dimension determines how many
features we input in a given time step.
The dynamic rnn operation
returns a two pool.
The first object in the two
pool is called output, and
it contains the activations for
every single time step.
We'll see why that might
be useful later on.
For now, we only care about
the activation for the last time step.
This is what the second
object state contains.
Finally, we take state and
pass it as the input to a DNN
to generate our predictions.
From this point forward, our code
is no different from any other DNN.