Now that we've learned how to get the data
in the right form from a table in our data
warehouse to our user interaction matrix
through mapping business centrical values
to row and column indices, do we need to
implement the ALS algorithm from scratch
to be able to use it and
learn the user and item embeddings?
Thankfully for us TensorFlow has the WALS
Matrix Factorization estimator to take
care of most of the work to
create our recommender system.
As with all canned estimators we just
need to connect some of the piping,
such as input functions, server input
functions, and the training evaluate loop,
and the estimator will take
care of everything else.
Because the WALS Matrix Factorization
estimator requires whole rows and columns,
we have to preprocess the data from our
data warehouse to be the right form.
Namely into a structure that we can store
into each SparseTensor for rows and
columns.
Here's an example of our
preprocessing step for
columns since we are grouping by item ID.
We will have similar code for
rows where we group by user ID instead.
So we want SparseTensors,
a hierarchical data structure.
What file type should we write
our preprocessed data to?
Here we're storing two arrays,
it's kind of painful to do this in CSV and
inefficient to do in JSON.
Therefore, our best option would
be to use TensorFlow records.
And look,
it's fairly easy to do in Python.
Here, we created a TFRecordWriter with
our specified path, users_for_item,
in this example.
For each item, we want to create
an example that stores our features,
which we can then write out as
serialized examples to our output file.
SparseTensors are hierarchical
data structures where indices and
values are stored, which in case will
be the user IDs, or the index of
the users from the user item interaction
matrix, and the ratings respectively.
We will also store the key,
which is the item index,
from the user interaction matrix.
This value is important to save,
which we'll see later,
because during the batching, they first
mention the SparseTensor indices tensor.
With rank two,
becomes the batch indices instead.
So we'll need the key data to replace the
incorrect overwrite when we're done with
the batching phase of the input function.
The indices and values can be quickly
converted into a SparseTensor using
tf.sparse_merge, where you need the ids,
values, and the vocab size,
such as a number of items in this example.
Now that we've learned how we should
pre process our data for WALS,
let's test your knowledge.
If we want to recommend items for
a user when we are writing out
to the TF Record file our key
train feature should be blank.
Our indices train feature should be blank.
And our values train
feature should be blank.
Chose the answer that
best fills in the blanks.
The correct answer is E.
Because we are recommending items, note
the plural for a user, note the singular.
We are in a situation where each
example will be a unique user per row.
There will be a variable
number of items per each user,
which will be the columns based on
what that user interacted with.
Some users interacting
with only a few items and
some users interacting with many items.
The indices tensor will be the item
indices or item IDs that have interacted
with and the values tensor will be
corresponding ratings at those user
item interaction points within
the user item interaction matrix.
Answer A however, should look familiar,
because that is the example
we just went through which is for
recommending users for an item.