Now, that we have learned how
WALS matrix factorization works for collaborative filtering,
let's put our new knowledge to action.
This lab demonstrates how to implement
a WALS matrix factorization approach to
do collaborative filtering using Google Analytics Data.
We'll be using most of the code that we learned earlier.
In later modules, we will combine this and content-based with a deep neural network,
and then learn how to productionize and automate
our solution using the Google Cloud platform ecosystem.
In this lab, we will be completing the to-dos in the WALS notebook.
Specifically, we will need to complete the decode example function,
where we decode the TF record protos and store the result in our dataset.
Also, we need to add
the WALS matrix factorization estimator within the batch predict function.
Making sure to include call to the input function,
serve an input function and our vocabularies.