Now, it's time for you to put your linear model to the test using the MNIST dataset.
How do you think it will do?
In this lab, you will import the training dataset of MNIST handwritten images,
you'll reshape and preprocess the image data,
then you'll set up your linear classifier model with ten classes,
one for each possible digits zero to nine.
Then, you'll define and create your estimator spec in
TensorFlow to create your custom estimator.
Then, you'll define and run your training and evaluate function to train against
the input dataset in 60,000 images and evaluate your model's performance.
But keep in mind, you have multiple attempts to start and stop each of these Qwiklabs.
So, don't worry if you didn't make it through all the way on the first try,
or if you want to reverse engineer the code in the notebook and
experiment with it after completing the lab, you can do so.
We'll review the solution together in the following video.