All right, as I mentioned,
here is our first lab.
We're going to build a linear model to
classify those handwritten digits from
the MNIST dataset inside of TensorFlow.
Let's go ahead and get started.
So here I am in my IPython Notebook
inside of Cloud Datalab.
The first thing that I've done,
I've already cloned the repo and
I've navigated to the lab's folder and
I've got my mnist_linear IPython Notebook.
And the first thing that you scroll
through you see that some of the code is
per-written for you, but
we didn't do everything for you.
So in order to define the model
you're going to see, well,
you going to create your linear_model.
We provided the train_input_fn and the
serving_input_fn but not the evaluation
input function which again is very
similar to the train_input_fn except for
a few key differentiating points.
We've got the custom estimator here.
That's going to take all those inputs and
get you ready for
the actual train_and_evaluate function.
Which is then going to be called and
what you're actually going to get when
you are running the model, you can get
your final accuracy for a linear model.
So let's start off from
all the way at the top.
So first off, we actually need to import
some helper functions which in this
particular case we've got numpy as
we're working with numpy arrays.
Those are expected inputs later on for
our training eval specs.
And we're working with output directories.
So we're going to use shutil and
tensorflow of course you
want to bring that in there.
And also get the latest
version of TensorFlow.
And then we actually need
to bring in our data.
So we're going to do,
grab the data from the tutorials.mnist.
We're going to import it,
we're going to use read_data_sets.
In the future, you're going to
be using the data sets API.
So you might get a warning actually
that this might be deprecated.
But for
now this is what we're going to be doing.
And you'll notice that we're not going to
reshape the data or do any of that here,
we're just bringing it in.
And then we're going to print out what
the current shape of the images are,
as well as associated labels width.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we're going to run,
We're running 1.8 for TensorFlow.
And we've got 55,000 images
in our training dataset.
They're of the shape 28 by 28, of course
that means they're 28 pixels by 28 pixels.
What do you think this 1 means?
Yeah, it's the channel depth, maybe 1.
55,000, and then we have the 10.
What do you think the 10 means?
Number of classes.
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8,
9 are the possible classes that
we're actually going to output.
We define those variables here as well.
So we have the HEIGHT that's expected is
28 pixels, WIDTH=28 pixels, NCLASSES=10.
Nothing you haven't sen before.
Now we want to plot these images, so
we can take a look at one particular one.
So I'm just saying, all right,
well, give me number 12.
Sure, so let's go ahead and
run this, we've got our variables.
Now show me this image, show me number 12.
Again, it's going to be 12 from the array,
so this is going to be whatever this is.
And we just know just because we're
interpreting it with our brains that this
is a 9 here.
But you also have the label for
it in your training [UNKOWN].
Okay, now for the fun part.
You've got your training data.
Now you actually need to build the
linear_model that's going to classify it.
So first things first,
you can have your linear_model defined and
you can ultimately return your logits and
your classes that you have.
For linear_models,
what are the components?
Well, you've got your X,
you've got your weights,
and you've got a bias
term associated with it.
So in this particular case, this is where
we're actually going to do the reshaping.
Let me just get these.
So x is going to be tf.
We're going to reshape.
What we're going to pass in?
Well, it's going to be an image.
And then we're actually going to
reshape it from a 2D, two dimensions,
HEIGHT and WIDTH, we're actually
going to flatten that all out.
You got to remember, this is trying
to bring it into just one dimension,
this is going to be our flatten operation.
And then for our weights,
we're going to get the variable
associated with the weights, and
we'll just specify that as W.
Get the HEIGHT and WIDTH,
and the total NCLASSES.
Which again, in this particular
case is just going to be the 10.
After that,
we're going to initialize the weights.
And initialize,
Your own weights and initial value.
And specify a bias term.
B, again, NCLASSES.
And then we'll initialize
the bias term to be zero.
And then, we actually have to get
our logits, which is just going to
be the matrix multiplication of
the the weights and our X here.
It's going to be matmul,
X and our weights.
And then the last thing you do for
a linear_model of course,
add in your bias term.
Great, so now we don't get any output and
that's just because you
defined your linear_model.
All right, now we actually need
to write the input functions.
They're three different pieces.
The training, the actual evaluation
that happens, and then the prediction.
So we've got your training
input functions here.
You've already done the reshaping where
you specify things like batch size,
the number of epochs and
the shuffling is going to be True for
your training input dataset.
Now what about for evaluation?
Now for the sake of going through this,
it's largely going to be the same.
Are you going to be using the same data
for training as you are for evaluation?
If you said yes,
[LAUGH] you're scaring me.
Don't forget you have a different data
set to actually do the evaluation set on.
This is going to be your
test batch of images.
And of course,
with your test batch of images you
also have your test batch of labels.
Let's do a specified batch_size,
then we have epochs 1 is fine,
because we only need to kind of go
through the entirety of it once
since we're not doing training.
We also don't need to shuffle it so
we're going to set shuffle=False.
And same queue_capacity is fine.
Great, we've got our eval_input_fn and
we have our serving_input_fn.
Custom estimator is written for
you as well.
And essentially in here, this is just for
each of the different logits that we
pass in, that we defined earlier for
our linear_model, that's where
you're actually going to get that.
And then you get the probabilities by
applying that softmax that you saw in
the lecture notes.
And then each of the different classes.
And associated probabilities with them,
you're actually going to get here.
And here is the fun part.
It's a little bit of a logic flow.
Based on a logic flow,
what we're actually going to be doing
is governed of course by the mode.
If it's training mode or
evaluation mode, then we actually
need to compute the loss function.
Which in this particular case,since
it's classification of course is that
cross_entropy.
We're doing a little bit of numerical
stabilization here with a reduced mean,
it's just everything that you see here.
And then for our classification models,
you need a performance metric which
in this particular case we're just
going to go with just accuracy.
And if we're in the training mode,
you're going to need a training operation,
which is going to take those learning
parameters like your learning_rate.
Those hyper parameters
that you're going to see,
we're going to define later on when
we call the train and evaluate.
And if you're not in training mode,
you don't need a training operation.
And just saving time you should not end
training or evaluation, AKA you are in
testing, you don't need three of
those things either, or prediction.
And then last but not least, you actually
return the estimators back which is where
what we're going to be
using a little bit later.
And to our favorite friend,
defining the actual,
what's actually going to be running your
model which is the train_and_evaluate
function that you see here.
So it actually needs to output
your results to a directory.
So we're actually going to
specify it a little bit later.
In the hyper parameters
that you're passing in,
things like your learning_rate, and
you can actually see those down here.
Your learning_rate and
the number of train_steps that you want.
In this particular case, we're just saying
1,000 with a learning_rate of 0.01.
And then you pass in the estimator.
Your training_spec.
Where you're actually exporting this to?
The eval_spec.
And then last but not least,
this is the estimator that we're
going to be actually being able to call.
And last but not least, we're specifying
when we're actually getting ready to
run this, we need to give a place
to actually store the results.
So your OUTDIR is, in this particular
case, you call it whatever you want.
We're just going to say mnist/learned.
And this is where you're using
shutil to basically say, hey,
if you're rerunning this multiple times
just blow out the entire directory and
then pass in these hyper parameters before
we finally get to call the last line in
the notebook, which is train_and_evaluate.
So let's go ahead and
get back to where we were here.
We've defined the model.
Let's run code that's going to
create our input functions.
We've got our custom estimator that's
going to do the heavy lifting.
And we're going to make it distributed
with our specs that we're going to
passing in.
And last but not least, we're going to
actually specify the directory,
pass in our hyper parameters and
train_and_evaluate.
So ultimately, at the end of the day,
we want to get just a single number for
how accurately this linear model
can classify these images.
As you can see, the first over on this,
I get an error, Likely a typo that I made.
get_variable not defined
all the way at the top.
Let's see if I had a simple typo.
Where's our model code?
tf,get_variable, tf,get_variable,
there we go.
[LAUGH] Let's run it all again.
All right, we're calling the function and
we're stepping through the training.
We can see the loss, we can see the loss
2.4 going down to optimized that loss
through gradient descent.
Loss for the final step.
And what you're looking for ultimately
is your the dictionary for final step.
1000, again that's where we stop it.
In my particular case, this might vary for
you may be between 85 and,
this is probably the best I've seen so
far.
We've got a 92% accurate linear_model for
class final images.
You might be happy with 92, maybe that's
good enough for your business application,
but for the rest of this course you'll be
working with other different models like
neural networks.
And particularly convolution neural
networks that can really interpret images
really, really well.
All right, we'll see you in the next lab.