Welcome back. I hope that lab opened your eyes to the usefulness of RNNs.
While RNNs are extremely powerful,
they can also be extremely finicky.
You have to consider the length of your sequences if you want them to be
overlapping or not overlapping and write a function to preprocess them in such a way.
For your model architecture,
you have to experiment with the number and type of RNN cells,
the size of the hidden state,
and how many hidden states to use when calculating your loss function.
Finally, you have to think about if and how to
incorporate non-sequential data into your sequential model.
If even one hyperparameter is off,
the whole model may perform badly as we saw in the lab.
So don't be discouraged if modeling time series data with
an RNN takes a lot of trial and error to get right.
This is normal.
If possible, be sure to start with easier to tune models like
linear DNN and CNN first to establish a benchmark.