We will start by talking about what high
performance means in this context and
providing a high level overview
of distributed architectures.
So what does high performance
machine learning mean to you?
Does it mean powerful,
the ability to handle large data sets?
Or maybe does it mean doing
it as fast as possible?
The ability to train for
long periods of time, achieving the best
possible accuracy, there's so many things.
But one key aspect is the time
taken to train a model.
If it takes six hours to train
a model on some hardware or
software architecture, but only three
hours to train the same same model
to the same accuracy on a different
hardware or software architecture.
I think we'll all agree
the second architecture
is twice as performant as the first one.
Now, notice that I said train
the model to the same accuracy.
Throughout this module, we will assume
that we're talking of models that
have same accuracy, or RMSE, or
whatever your evaluation measure is.
Obviously, when we talk about high
performance machine learning models,
accuracy is important.
We aren't just going to
consider that in this module.
The rest of the courses in this
specialization will look at how to build
more accurate ML models and there,
we'll be looking at model architectures
that will help us get
to a desired accuracy.
Here in this course, we'll look
solely at infrastructure performance.
Besides the time to train,
there is one other aspect, budget.
You often have a training budget.
You might be able to train
faster on better hardware, but
that hardware might cost more, so
you may have to make the explicit choice
to train on slightly
slower infrastructure.
So when it comes to your training budget,
you have three considerations,
three levers that you can adjust.
These are time, cost, and scale.
Now, how long are you willing
to spend on the model training?
This might be driven by
the business use case.
If you're training a model everyday, so
as to recommend products the next day,
then your training has to
finish within 24 hours.
Realistically, you'll also need time
to deploy, to AB test and all that.
So your actual budget
might be only 18 hours, so
then how much are you willing to spend on
model training in terms of computing cost?
These too is a business decision.
You don't want to train for
18 hours everyday if the incremental
benefit of this is not sufficient.
Scale is another aspect of your budget.
Models differ in terms of how
computationally expensive they are.
Even keeping to the same model,
you have a choice of how much
data you're going to train on.
Generally, the more data,
the more accurate the model.
But there are diminishing returns
to larger and larger data sizes, so
your time and cost budget may
also dictate the data set size.
Similarly, you often have a choice
between training on a single,
more expensive machine or
multiple cheaper machines.
But to take advantage of this,
you may have to write your code
somewhat differently, and
that's another aspect of scale.
Also, you have the choice of starting
from an earlier model checkpoint and
training for just a few steps.
Typically, this will converge faster
than training from scratch each time.
This compromise might allow you to reach
the desired accuracy faster and cheaper.
In addition, there are ways to tune
performance to reduce the time,
reduce the cost or increase the scale.
In order to understand what these are,
it helps to understand that model training
performance will be bound
by one of three things.
Input/output, which is how fast you
can get data into the model for
each training step.
The CPU, which is how fast you can compute
the gradient in each training step.
And memory,
how many weights can you hold in memory so
that you can do the matrix multiplications
in memory or do you use the GP or TPU.
Your ML training will be I/O bound
if the number of inputs is large.
Heterogeneous, requiring parsing or
if the model is so
small that the computer
requirements are trivial.
This also tends to be the case if
the input data is on a storage system
with very low throughput.
Your ML training CPU bound
if the I/O is simple but
the model involves lots of
expensive computations.
You will also encounter this situation
if you're running a model
on underpowered hardware.
Your ML training might be memory bound if
the number of inputs is really large or
if the model is complex and
has lots of free parameters.
You'll also face memory limitations
if your accelerator doesn't
have enough memory.
So knowing what you're bound by, you
can look at how to improve performance.
If you're IO bound,
look at storing the data more efficiently
on a storage system with higher
throughput or parallelizing the reads.
Although it's not ideal, you might also
consider reducing the batch size so
that you're reading
less data in each step.
If you are a CPU bound, see if you can
run the training on a faster accelerator.
GPUs keep getting faster, so
move to a newer generation processor.
And if you're using Google Cloud, you
also have the option of running on TPUs.
Even if it's not ideal,
you might consider using a simpler model,
a less computationally expensive
activation function or
simply just train for fewer steps.
If you are memory bound, see if you can
add more memory to the individual workers.
Again, this may not be ideal, but
you could also consider using
fewer layers in your model.
Reducing the batch size can also
help with memory bound ML systems.