We've talked about the time to train.
But there is another aspect to performance, predictions.
During inference, you'll have performance considerations as well.
If you doing batch prediction,
the considerations are very similar to that of training.
You're concerned with things such as time.
How long does it take for you to do all of your predictions?
This might be driven by a business need as well.
So, for example, if you're doing product recommendations for the next day,
you might want recommendations for the top 20 percent of
users precomputed and available in five hours,
if it takes 18 hours to do the full training.
You'll also want to consider cost.
What predictions are you doing and how much do you
precompute is going to be driven by cost considerations?
Then, there's scale.
Do you have to do all of this on a single machine or can
you distribute it safe to multiple workers?
What kind of hardware is available on these workers?
Do they for example have GPUs?
If you're doing online prediction,
the performance considerations are quite different.
This is because the end user is actually waiting for the prediction.
So, let's take a look at how it's different.
You typically cannot distribute the prediction graph,
instead you carry out the computation for one end user on one machine.
However, you almost always scale out the predictions onto multiple workers.
Essentially, each prediction is handled by a microservice and you can replicate,
and scale out the predictions using Kubernetes or App Engine.
Cloud ML Engine predictions or higher level abstraction,
but they are equivalent to doing this.
The performance consideration is not
how many training steps you can carry out per minute,
but how many queries you can handle per second.
The unit of this queries per second is often called QPS,
that's the performance target that you need to hit.
When you design for higher performance,
you want to consider training and prediction separately,
especially if you will be doing online predictions.
As I suggested in my line about precomputed batch predictions for
the top 20 percent of users and handling the rest of your users via online prediction,
performance considerations will also involve striking the right balance.
Ultimately, you will know the exact trade-off,
is it a 20 percent or 10 percent or 25 percent,
only after you build your system and start to measure things.
However, unless you plan to be able to do both batch predictions and online predictions,
you will be stuck with a solution that doesn't meet all of your needs.
The idea behind this module and this course in general,
is so that you're aware of all of the possibilities.
Once you are aware that it can be done,
it's actually not that difficult to accomplish.
The technical part is usually quite straightforward,
especially if you're using TensorFlow on a capable cloud platform.