In the previous lessons, we quickly
reviewed BigQuery and python notebooks.
Let's now look at them in combination
because the two technologies
complement each other very well.
So here, I have the query as a string and
I'm using a Python package
google.datalab.bigquery.
That's Python package.
To execute the query, that's the execute.
So I'm take the query, passing in
the string and calling the execute method.
And then I'm taking the result
that comes back and
converting the result
into a Pandas data frame.
DF is a Pandas data frame, df.head shows
the first few rows of the result set.
Now, this is an extremely powerful
paradigm because BigQuery
allows you to compute aggregate statistics
on very large data sets interactively.
And then, you can use Python plotting
commands to create impact for
visualizations.
For example, take this, so
that's what you're seeing here.
So using Pandas and
BigQuery together in a notebook.
The combination of Python and
BigQuery in a notebook rocks.
In this code snippet,
get_distinct_values is like
the code in the previous slide,
it's like this code.
This is essentially carried
out using a SQL query,
and there's probably a count
distinct in the SQL and
the result is coming
back into a data frame.
And once we have that data frame,
we can now use the Pandas
functionality to sort and to plot.
So we are using BigQuery to carry out
aggregation using SQL on millions
of rows in the first command, and
then getting back a Pandas data frame and
using the Pandas functionality to sort and
to plot the data that we got back.
And we are basically getting the results
in a Python notebook, so we get to work
interactively in a Python notebook on
data sets that are tremendously large.
So this is what you will
do in the first lab.