As we saw on the last specialization,
there are no globally optimal values for
hyperparameters, only
problem-specific optima.
Because we expect to do hyperparameter
tuning, our system needs to support it.
By which I mean, operate multiple
experiments in parallel and ideally,
using early experiments to
guide later ones automatically.
Cloud ML Engines supports hyperparameter
tuning using a variety of algorithms, and
you can read more about the specific
algorithms in this paper.
The Model Evaluation and Validation
components have one responsibility.
To ensure that the models are good,
before moving them into
the production environment.
The goal is to ensure that users'
experiences aren't degraded.
There are two main things that we care
about with respect to model quality.
How safe the model is to serve, and
the model's prediction quality.
A safe to serve model won't crash or cause
errors in the serving system when being
loaded or when sent on expected inputs.
It also shouldn't use more than the
expected amount of resources, like memory.
Model evaluation is part of the iterative
process where teams try and
improve their models.
However, because it's expensive
to test on live data,
experiments are generally
run offline first.
And it's in this setting where
model evaluation takes place.
Model evaluation consists of a person or
a group of people assessing the model with
respect to some business-relevant metric,
like AUC or cost-weighted error.
If the model meets their criteria,
then it can be pushed into production for
a live experiment.
In contrast to the model evaluation
component, which is human facing,
the model validation component is not.
Instead, it evaluates the model
against fixed thresholds and
alerts engineers when things go awry.
One common test is to look at
performance by slice of the input.
For example,
business stakeholders may care strongly
about a particular geographic market.
This is also another junction
where ML fairness comes up.
Both of these modules are a part of TFX,
Google's internal production ML system.
We've already open sourced
some of these TFX libraries,
including TF Transform,
TF Model Analysis, and TF Serving.