Hello, my name is Lak,
and I led the team that put together this course and this specialization.
We started out this course by explaining what recommendation systems are.
We said that when you watch a video on YouTube
and you see a list of suggested videos to watch next,
that list is being built by recommendation machine learning model.
You can't just build a recommendation engine and ML model and call it a day,
you also need to build the entire end-to-end system.
We looked at how to build content-based recommendation systems,
where the system recommends items to
users based on metadata that's known about the items.
We then learned how to implement
collaborative filtering where you don't have any metadata about the products or users,
instead you learn about item similarity and
user similarity from ratings data or interaction data.
Because this interaction matrix is very large,
we use the alternating least squares algorithm to
factorize the interaction matrix into user factors and item factors.
Then, if we need to find whether a user will like a particular movie,
it's as simple as taking the row corresponding to
the user and the column corresponding to the movie,
and multiplying them to get the predicted rating.
To recommend movies to users,
we can then recommend the movies that we predict they will rate the highest.
We did this in TensorFlow.
Then, we looked at how to build a hybrid recommendation system.
The hybrid model uses all the data available and
connects all of these models together into a machine learning pipeline.
Finally, we learned how to productionize
and automate the machine learning pipeline in order to
build and continuously retrain an end-to-end recommendation system.
We were able to orchestrate the continuous retraining of
the recommendation system as new ratings data keeps coming in from users.
With this, we come to the end of this course on recommendation systems.
Thank you for accompanying us on this journey.