Hi. I'm Alex, a technical curriculum developer for Google Cloud.
You saw the demo earlier where we classified a simple cloud with the Vision API.
Now, let's make the problem harder by asking more of the model.
Now, let's say we want to predict weather patterns.
This means we need to identify not just that there's a cloud,
but also what type of cloud.
For example, a cirrus cloud is usually associated with
fair weather whereas a cumulonimbus cloud usually foreshadows rain.
So, let's revisit our Vision API and see how well it does on this new problem.
After I uploaded the image to the Vision API,
here are the results for the labels it inferred.
We see that it still knows that it's a cloud with 95 percent accuracy but it has
no concept that it's a cirrus cloud and
even incorrectly guesses that it's a cumulus at 85 percent.
The pre-trained model likely was never taught to
recognize cloud types to this granularity.
We need something a little more custom that we can train ourselves.
So now, as an ML practitioner,
you're next instinct would be to try AutoML vision.
Provided we have a training dataset,
which in this case would be pictures of different types
of clouds with the corresponding label,
we can upload that to Auto ML vision and let it build a custom model for us.