The big take away here is not what
we did but what we didn't do.
As we talked about at the beginning,
typically when building a custom model,
here are several steps which
are complex and time intensive.
With AutoML,
we don't have to do any of that.
However, as great as AutoML is,
it can't solve every ML problem,
which is why you learned how to build
a CNN by hand earlier in the course.
Behind the scenes, AutoML is
powered by the latest ML research.
While your model trains,
the AutoML platform actually trains and
evaluates multiple models and
compares them against each other.
This NAS net approach or
Neural Architecture Search,
produces an ensemble of ML models and
chooses the best one.
Like Go and self driving cars,
deep learning is now doing
deep learning as you saw with
the Neural Architecture Search.
But how well does a co-list model you
build with AutoML compare with some of
the other image classification models that
you've heard about as part of this course?
Remember the image that
competition launched in 2010, and
the winning CNN network Alex net in 2012?
Then, Google created it's Inception
network for image classification,
which was revolutionary at that time for
the depth of the network.
This graph is a refresh of the best
models for image published in 2017.
The x-axis is model size,
the y-axis is accuracy.
What you want is a small model, left on
the x, with great accuracy, top of the y.
The goal is that green dot there.
Our world has been trending towards big,
heavy models that aren't exactly
like a brain, that's the black line.
AutoML, powered by the NASNet,
is shown in the red line.
The AutoML networks are smaller and
more efficient.
I'll provide a link to the Google AI blog
so you can track the latest developments.
But first, it's time to try
your hand at both AutoML and
the Vision API that you saw earlier.