So as we said previously,
sequence data typically can be represented
as observations of a certain number of
characteristics of an event over time.
How would you convert this into
a vector for input or output?
How would you take our sequence data,
which looks like this table or
this graph, and arrange it so
that it's a single row of your dataset?
The simplest method is to take a window of
fixed size and slide it over our dataset,
and then to concatenate the observations
within the window to create a vector.
Let's say that we only have one
characteristic that we're observing over
time, the price of oil, and
we'd like to predict the future price
at some single later time point.
First, we determine a size for our window,
and then slide the window over the data.
Assuming we have observations
at t different time points, and
our sliding window is n time units wide,
and we have a stride of 1,
how many rows will there
be in our training set?
The answer is t minus n.
And this expression reveals the tension
between the width of our sliding window
and the amount of data that
it will ultimately have.
The wider our window,
the fewer examples our model will see.
But generally, this only makes a
difference when you don't have much data.
Assuming our window size is ten minutes,
after sliding our window over our data,
we will have a table with 11 columns.
And a number of rows equal to
the length of our sequence minus ten.
So what's the good size for
our sliding window?
Unfortunately, there's no
simple answer to that.
It will depend on what you're modeling.
And this means you'll need to
consult with domain experts.
Sometimes the most important
effects are short-term,
like predicting the next
day's temperature.
Here, for instance, I've graphed
the daily temperature for 2017 for
Seattle, Washington.
Notice how if you look
at any one data point,
its neighbors are generally
relatively close.
Sometimes the most important effects are
quite separated in time, such as if you're
using rainfall to predict crop
yield at the end of the season.
One method that you can use to
determine an appropriate amount of lag
is to look at the correlation
between an observation at time t and
the observations that preceded it.
Then you pick a threshold, say,
seven days based on how much each
previous observation correlates.
Let's pretend we're
talking about a sprinkler.
Assuming that you knew the data were
periodic, and that the rotation speed and
water pressure of the sprinkler
tube was constant, and
that the sprinkler made one
full rotation in one minute.
What would be a good choice for
our sliding window length?
The answer in this case is that
after including one minute of prior
observations, prior time points
provide no additional information.