Hi there. Vijay here again.
One of the most common questions we find in machine learning is how to classify text.
In this module, we'll look at different ways of working with text,
and how to create your own text classification models.
We'll start with discussing how to work with text,
then we'll talk about how we can classify text using machine learning.
We'll close with a discussion about Python versus native Tensorflow functions for
pre-processing text and some tips for productionizing your text classification model.
Up until now, we've been working directly with numbers.
In our first labs using sequences,
those numbers represented the height of water from a sprinkler.
Our most recent lab,
they represented temperature readings.
However, not all sequences are numeric.
Take natural language for example.
The words in a sentence are a sequence.
Why? Because the order of the words matter.
If you change the order of words in a sentence,
it no longer makes sense.
So, sequential models allow us to capture
the meaning of sentences better than non-sequential models.
So, what practical use cases can we tackle with natural language?