In this module,
our high level goal is to help you learn
how to better manage data dependencies.
To do that, we'll first review all of the
many and surprising ways that data affect
the model and how you can protect
your model's performance and
your system's stability all while
keeping your team productive.
Then we'll build a pipeline that
demonstrates how one sort of dependency
can be manged within the code itself.
And then finally,
we'll put on our detective hats and
practice debugging
models in production and
try to explain our observations in
terms of mismanaged dependencies.
To motivate this section on how to adapt
to change, consider these four things and
ask yourself which is
least likely to change?
An upstream model,
a data source maintained by another team,
the relationship between features and
labels, or the distributions of inputs.
The answer is that all of them can and
often do change.
Let's talk about how and
what to do when that happens.
In one scenario, you've created a model
to predict demand for umbrellas,
that excerpts as input and output from a
more specialized weather prediction model.
Unbeknownst to you and
the owners of the model, this model has
been trained on the wrong years of data.
Your model however is fit to the upstream
model's outputs, what could go wrong?
One day the model owners silently push
a fix and the performance of your model
which expected the old model
distribution of data drops.
The old data had below average rainfall,
and
now you're underpredicting the days
when you need an umbrella.
Here's another scenario.
Your small data science team has convinced
the web development team to let you ingest
their traffic logs.
Later, the web development
team refactors their code and
changes their logging format but
continue publishing in the old format.
At some point though they stop
publishing on the old format and
they forget to tell your team.
Your model's performance degrades after
getting an unexpectedly high number of
null features.
There are two ways of fixing this.
Firstly, you should think carefully before
consuming data from sources when there's
a chance you won't know
about changes to them.
Secondly, you can make a local
version of upstream models and
update it on your schedule.
Sometimes the set of features that
the model's been trained on including many
that were added indiscriminately, and
these sometimes worsen model performance.
For example,
under pressured during a cold spring,
your team decided to include in number of
features without thinking rigorously
about their relationship at the label.
One of the miscausal, the others
are merely correlated with the causal one.
The model however can't distinguish
between causality and correlation and
takes all features into account equally.
Months later, the correlated features
become decorrelated with the label and
are thus no longer predictive.
The model's performance suffers.
To address this, features should always
be scrutinized before being added.
And all features should be subjected
to leave one out evaluations
to assess their importance.