Earlier in this module,
we talked about how in the context
of ingesting an upstream model
our models performance would degrade if
it expected one input and got another.
The statistical term for changes in
the likelihood of observed values
like model inputs is changes
in the distribution.
And it turns out that the distribution
of the data can change for
all sorts of reason.
Let's review some examples.
For example, sometimes
the distribution of the label changes.
We've looked at the natality dataset in
BigQuery and tried to predict baby weight.
Some of you may have noticed that baby
weight has actually changed over time.
It peaked in the 1980s and
has since been declining.
In this graph, I've depicted the
distributions of baby weights for 1969 and
in 1984.
And note that in 1969 babies weighed
significantly less than they did in 1984.
When the distribution of the label
changes, it could mean that
the relationship between features and
labels is changing as well.
At the very least, it's likely
that our model's predictions which
will typically match the distribution
of the labels in the training set
will be significantly less accurate.
Sometimes it's not the labels but the
features that change their distribution.
For example, say you've trained your model
to predict population movement patterns
using ZIP code as a feature.
Surprisingly, ZIP codes aren't fixed.
The government releases new ones and
deprecates old ones every year.
Now as a ML practitioner, you know
that ZIP codes aren't really numbers.
So you've chosen to represent them
as categorical feature columns, but
this might lead to problems.
If you chose to specify a vocabulary,
but set the number of out of vocabulary
buckets to zero and
didn't specify a default.
Then the distribution may become
skewed toward the default value,
which is negative 1.
And this might be problematic because
the model maybe forced to make predictions
in regions of the future space, which were
not well represented in the training data.
There's another name for when models
are asked to make predictions on points in
future space that are far away from the
training data, and that's extrapolation.
Extrapolation means to generalize outside
the bounds of what we've previously seen.
Interpolation is the opposite,
it means to generalize within the bounds
of what we've previously seen.
Interpolation is always much easier.
For example, let's say the model got to
see the green data, but not the blue data.
The red line reflects a linear
regression on the green data.
Predictions in the green region
are interpolated and reasonably accurate.
In contrast, predictions in the blue
ribbon are extrapolated and
are increasingly inaccurate the farther
we get from the green region.
You can protect yourself from
changing distributions using a few
different methods.
The first thing you can do is to
be vigilant through monitoring.
You can look at the descriptive
summaries of your inputs and
compare them to what the model is seen.
If for example, the mean or
the variance has changed substantially,
then you can analyze this new segment of
the input space to see if
the relationships learned still hold.
You can also look to see whether the
models residuals, that is the difference
between it's predictions and the labels
has changed as a function of the input.
If for example, you used to have small
errors at one side of the input and
large in another, and now it's switched.
This could be evidence of
a change in the relationship.
Finally, if you have reason to
believe that the relationship is
changing over time.
You can force the model to treat more
recent observations as more important by
writing a custom loss function or
by retraining the model
on the most recent data.