When leading a team of engineers,
many decisions are informed by technical debt and other sorts of cost-benefit analysis.
The best teams get very high rates of return on their investments.
With that in mind, let's consider a few scenarios.
Let's pretend that you're the leader of a team of
engineers and you're nearing the end of a code sprint.
One of the teams goals for the sprint,
is to increase performance on the model by five percent.
Currently however, the best-performing model is
only marginally better than what was around before.
One of the engineers acknowledges this,
but still insist that it's worth spending time doing an extensive ablation analysis,
where the value of an individual features
computed by comparing it to a model train without it.
What might this engineer be concerned about?
The engineer might be concerned about legacy and bundled features.
Legacy features are older features that were added,
because they were valuable at the time.
But since then, better features have been added,
which have made them redundant without our knowledge.
Bundled features on the other hand,
are features that were added as part of a bundle,
which collectively are valuable but individually may not be.
Both of these features represent additional unnecessary data dependencies.
In another scenario, another engineer has found
a new data source that is very much related to the label.
The problem is that, it's in a unique format and there's no parser written in Python,
which is what your code base is written in.
Thankfully, there is a parser on the web,
but it's closed source and written in a different language.
The engineers thinking about the model performance,
but something in the back of your mind seems wrong.
What is it? It's the smell.
Now, really there's an idea for this and it's called code smell.
It applies in ML as well.
In this case, you might be thinking,
"I wonder what introducing code that we can't inspect and
unable to easily modify into our testing in production frameworks will do."