A common use case is your organization has a multi-cloud solution,
and data already exists on another cloud provider.
The cloud to cloud transfer service transfers
data from an online data source to a data sink.
Your data source can be an Amazon simple storage service or Amazon S3 bucket,
it can be an HTTP or HTTPS location,
a Google Cloud Storage bucket.
Now why, would your source via Google Cloud Storage bucket?
Well, if you're transferring data between regions within Google,
your data sink or the destination is always a Google Cloud storage bucket.
The GS Command Line Tool also enables you to
transfer data between Google Cloud storage and other locations.
While you can use gsutil to work with Amazon S3 buckets and
transfer data from Amazon S3 to Google Cloud storage,
the storage transfer service is highly recommended for this use.
Creating a transfer job is simple.
You first specify the source and sink,
like from S3 to GCS.
Then you configure the transfer as
a one time job or a routine transfer job and that's it.