The last data migration scenario we will cover,
is data that already exists in your database application.
There are several options for migrating
existing databases to Google Cloud's fully managed options.
These include the BigQuery data transfer service,
migrations to Cloud SQL,
and Spanner for your relational data bases.
And Cloud Dataproc for your Hadoop jobs and more.
It can be overwhelming when choosing from different database options.
We've broken down the decision path here.
Do you have structured log data from monitoring IoT applications?
If so, consider BigTable or Spanner.
What about relational data from an on-premise MySQL database?
For that, consider Cloud SQL or Spanner.
What about migrating your data analytics and reporting warehouse?
For that, consider BigQuery.
What about your existing legacy Hadoop jobs?
For those, I'll use Dataproc,
and run those same jobs inside of a fully managed service.
You've already worked with BigQuery before as part of this course.
But did you know there's
a fully managed data import service for bringing in data sets from AdWords,
DoubleClick, and YouTube into BigQuery?
Meet the BigQuery data transfer service.
Now you can use BigQuery to
analyze the results of your online marketing campaigns for example.
When looking to migrate your on-premise database application,
like Oracle, SQL Server, or MySQL,
consider working with a partner to set up a migration plan,
and switch over your on-premise infrastructure to a no NoOps fully managed solution,
like Cloud SQL, or SQL Spanner.
Lastly, if you have existing MapReduce Hadoop jobs,
you can bring these over too and run them, within Cloud Dataproc.
You practiced running a few of these jobs in a VM,
in the very first part of the ML on GCP course.
You can also leverage and work with our partner ecosystem,
to assist you in the migration.