Content based recommendations
used embedding spaces for
items only, whereas now for collaborative
filtering we're learning where users and
items fit within a common embedding space
along dimensions they have in common.
We can choose a number of
dimensions to represent them in
either using human derived features or
using latent features that
are under the hood of our preferences,
which we'll learn how to find very soon.
Each item has a vector within its
embedding space that describes the items
amount of expression of each dimension.
Each user also has a vector
within its embedding space
that describes how strong their
preference is for each dimension.
For now, let's keep things simple and
keep things just one
dimension looking at items.
And we'll get back to multi-dimensional
embeddings later, and how users fit in.
We'll start simple and
then build ourselves up.
We could organize items, let's say movies
by similarity in one dimension, for
example, of where they fall
on the spectrum of movies for
children to movies for adults.
Let's say we have the movie Shrek,
we want to know where it falls on this
children to adult movie spectrum.
Using our own built up knowledge
we would say that Shrek would
probably go to the far left because it's
an animated movie mainly for children.
What about the movie
The Dark Knight Rises?
Where do we think it goes along our axis?
Well The Dark Knight Rises, we know, is
definitely a more adult movie than Shrek,
so it should go to the right
of Shrek on the spectrum.
Now that we have two movies placed,
things start to get a bit harder because
we have three choices to decide from.
Here we have Harry Potter that we
want to place along our spectrum.
Does it go to the left of Shrek,
to the right of The Dark Knight Rises or
somewhere in between?
From our internal
representations of these movies,
we can guess that Harry Potter goes
between Shrek and The Dark Knight Rises.
It definitely has more adult themes than
Shrek, but still not as much violence or
adult themes as The Dark Knight Rises.
Exactly where in between it
should go we will get to soon.
All right, three movies placed,
more to go.
We now have four choices of where
to place the movie Memento.
What to do?
Memento has some very adult themes, and
our knowledge would probably place it even
farther right than The Dark Knight Rises.
Lastly, we want to place
the Triplets of Belleville.
As you can see, every time we add a movie,
the number of positions we can
place it in relative to the other
movies increases by one.
Imagine if we had thousands and
thousands of movies.
The Triplets of Belleville is pretty far
along the children's movie scale, but
not quite as much as Shrek, so
this is where we will put it.
However, this is all very qualitative,
with just some unknown relative
position along a number line.
Can we make this a little more
quantitative, maybe with some numbers?
We've now added values on where we think
these movies lie along our number line,
high negative values are considered
very much children's movies, and
high positive values
are considered very adult.
Movies close to zero
are basically half way between,
what we'd say is a very a childish and
very adult.
We've essentially created a 1D embedding
space with our coordinate system and
our five points could have these values,
indicating where they sit on the
children's movie, adult movie spectrum.
Now, you can calculate
similarities by distance matrix,
between the points in
our coordinate system.
Those that are closer, or
have a smaller distance,
are more similar, at least with respect
to this children adult factor we chose.
Based on these values, along this axis,
The Dark Knight Rises and
Memento are the most similar movies.
However, even if two movies are very close
in this one-dimensional projection using
child-adult spectrum, in other projections
using other features of the movies,
they could be extremely far apart.
Let's now add a second dimension to
calculate similarities between movies, for
example, where movies fall on
the art house, blockbuster spectrum.
Not only have we arranged
the movies along the children,
adult movie spectrum, they are now
spread out along the second dimension.
As we add dimensions our embedding spaces
grow exponentially larger and become
sparser and sparser with large voids
between points in the embedding space.
In this 2D embedding space
coordinate system we created,
our five points could have these values
indicating where they sit on both
a children's movie adult movie spectrum,
and the arthouse blockbuster spectrums.
As we can see, the movies points in our
two-dimensional embedding space have
the same coordinate values as along our
original children adult spectrum, however,
they have now been spread out over our
new arthouse blockbuster spectrum.
The points haven't changed at all,
but our coordinate system has.
Coordinate systems are important,
they are just a way to
describe points within space.
Based on these values in our new
two-dimensional embedding space,
The Dark Rises and
Memento are no longer the closest, or
most similar movies, at least not
using the dot product distance metric,
the two closest are now Harry Potter and
Shrek.
In fact, our previous closest
aren't now even the second closest,
which goes to Harry Potter and
The Dark Knight Rises.
This is due to how close these three
movies are along the blockbuster axis,
which is dominating in
the dot product calculation.
So how do we apply these embeddings to
the user-item interaction matrix so
that we can infer how unknown
interactions can be rated?
Well, we've already talked about the item
embedding space on the two dimensions
that we choose, children adult, and
art house blockbuster spectrums.
But what about the user embeddings?
Let's say we knew where a user could
be placed along both of our dimensions,
giving us their coordinate
values in our embedding space.
Each user would have a two-dimensional
coordinate, and each
item would also have a two-dimensional
coordinate within our space.
To find out the interaction
value between users and
items, we simply take the dot
product between each user item pair.
The IJth interaction value is the inner
product of the I th user barrier and
the Jth item vector.
Let's see how that looks
in our embedding space.
Going back to our coordinate
system plot from before,
we have our movies plotted in the two
dimensional embedding space at their
coordinate values, based on where they
fall within the two vectors we chos.
We've also now added the users
at their respective coordinates.
So, what should we
recommendation to each user?
Let's look at the leftmost user.
To find the answer to what movie
the leftmost user should watch,
all we need to do is take the dot
product between the user and each movie.
In this example, we chose to
return the top two highest movies,
which end up being Shrek and The Triplets
of Belleville because they had the two
highest dot products for
that user across all the other movies.
Now this might seem obvious
from looking at this graph,
however it is not as easy for a computer
to see this, because our trained eyes and
the neural networks in our brains have
had decades of experience to see.
Yet, this is only with two dimensions and
with few items.
If we were to increase the dimensionality,
we humans would have a very difficult time
discerning which movies are the closest.
We would probably stop inspecting and
just take the doubt product.
The same can be done for items.
Let's say we want to see what
movies closest to Shrek are.
Instead of taking the dot product
between a user and all the items,
we take an item of interest and take
the dot product with all the other items.
In the example,
we once again are returning the top two,
which turns out to be Harry Potter and
The Triplets of Belleville.
You do the exact same to find users
similar to users of interest by taking
a dot product between users.
So as we can see, users and
items can be represented as d-dimensional
points within an embedding space.
In our example, we choose some
human experience based factors for
each of our two dimensions, and
humans manually scored each movie,
giving it a value for
each dimension along its axis.
We did the same for evaluating each user's
coordinates in our embedding space.
Well, this works great for toy examples
with four users and five items, but
it quickly becomes unscalable as more
users and items are added to the system.
Furthermore, as we saw in the last course,
when psychologists used what they thought
would be good features for embedding,
it turned out not to be that great.
Here are human-derived features
may not be the best choice.
So how can we choose then?
Fortunately for us,
the embeddings can be learned from data.
Instead of defining the factors that we
will assign values along our coordinate
system, we will use the user item
interaction data to learn the latent
factors that best factorize the user
item interaction matrix into a user
factor embedding and
item factor embedding.
We are essentially compressing the data,
our very sparse interaction matrix, and
relying on the generalities within,
which are the latent factors.
You might be reminded of PCA, SVD, or
other dimensionality reduction techniques,
like we covered in the last course,
for reusable embeddings.
The user interaction matrix factorization
splits this very large user by item matrix
into two smaller matrices of row factors,
which are users in this case, and
column factors,
which are movies in this case.
You can think of these two factor matrices
as essentially user and item embeddings.
Now, you might be wondering why matrix U
has two columns and matrix V has two rows.
Well, this is simply dimensionality
of our learned embedding space
of our latent features.
Remember, a latent feature is a feature
that we are not directly observing or
defining, but are instead inferring
through our model from the other
variables that are directly observed,
namely the user item interaction pairs.
Just like for other dimensionality
reduction techniques like PCA and
SBD, the number of latent features is
a hyperparameter that we can use as a knob
for the tradeoff between more
information compression and
more reconstruction error from
our approximated matrices.
Just how much space are we saving?
Let's say there are u users and
i items, which gives our user item
interaction matrix a, a size of u by i.
If our website has 50 million users and
10 thousand movies, that's already
500 billion interaction pairs.
On the other hand,
if we can have k laden features,
then u will be u by k elements and
v will have k by i elements.
The total space is just the number
of users plus the number
of movies times the number
of latent features.
Even with 10 latent features in this case,
it is still a thousand times
less space than before.
As long as the number of latent features
is less than half the harmonic mean
of the number of users and
the number of items, this will save space.
For this hypothetical website, that
would be almost 10,000 latent features,
9,998 to be precise, which is almost as
if we hadn't embedded the movies at all,
since there were 10,000
movies to begin with.
Each movie is essentially
it's own feature.
To make a prediction,
we simply take the dot product
of a user with the item factors or
an item with the user factors, and
we will get a prediction value for
that particular rating.
In this example,
we want to predict the rating for
user four for the movie Shrek,
which is the third column.
So we multiply 0.1 with 1, and
1 with a -1, to get a value of -0.9.
Harry Potter gets a prediction of -0.11,
and
The Triplets of Belleville also
gets a prediction of a -0.9.
If we were recommending the highest
predicted unwatched movie to user four out
of the movies shown,
that would be Harry Potter because
it has the highest predicted score.
Now it's time to test your knowledge about
finding the best recommendations based on
user and item similarities.
Based on this user item
interaction matrix of users and
movies, which movie should user 4 watch?
The correct answer is A.
To find this answer, we should have
calculated all the dot products between
user four's user factor vector and
all the movie factor vectors.
User four's predicted rating for Harry
Potter by the dot product is a -0.11.
The Triplets of Belleville and
Shrek are both a -0.9.
The Dark Knight Rises is 1 and
Memento is 0.91.
Remember we are just recommending
the top one movies in this question, so
we should return the max dot
product between user four's,user
factor vectors of 0.1 and 1,
with all the movie factor vectors.
So, why is the answer Harry Potter when
The Dark Knight Rises has the highest
dot product out of all the movies?
The reason is because the user has
already rated The Dark Knight Rises,
implicitly in this example, and
thus we don't want to recommend
that the user watch a movie they've
already seen, because most users know
whether they liked something in the past,
and instead, want to watch something new.
Therefore, we must filter out all off the
movies that have already been rated, and
then from the resulting subset,
choose the top one.
This results in Harry Potter,
although the negative dot product,
which means that the movie is predicted
to be below neutral sentiment, but
has the highest dot product value
out of the unwatched movies.