So we've now learned how the user
item interaction matrix works, and
how we can create user embeddings and
item embeddings within the same latent
space, which can be learned from data.
So what machine learning
algorithms can help us with this?
Collaborative filtering uses a user
item interaction matrix, and
it is a 2D table that provides ratings for
user item pairs.
These matrices are usually very sparse
because there's a large number of users
and a large number of items,
which creates a massive cartesian product.
These gargantuan matrices normally need to
be shrunk down to a more attractable size,
for example, through matrix factorization.
With this method, we first factorize
the user interactions matrix
into two smaller matrices,
user factors and item factors.
If given a user ID, we can multiply item
factors to get the predicted ratings for
all items.
Also vice versa, if given a movie ID,
we can multiply by user factors to get
the predicted rating for all users.
Now that we have all the predicted
ratings, we can return the top k rated
items back to the user, who can now
possibly make a better decision.
We want to factorize our user interaction
matrix, A, into the two smaller matrices,
user factor matrix, U,
and item factor matrix, V.
Because this is an approximation, we want
to minimize the squared error between
the original user interaction matrix and
the product of the two factor matrices.
This resembles a least squares problem,
and there are several ways to solve it.
But which one should we choose?
One method is to use
the classic learning algorithm,
stochastic gradient descent, or SGD.
Let's go through the strengths and
weaknesses of using SGD.
SGD is very flexible.
It can be used for many different
types of problems and loss functions.
And we probably already have
a lot of experience using it, so
plus one to the strengths.
SGD is also parallel, which is awesome
because then we can scale out our matrix
factorization and
quickly tackle much larger problems.
Another plus one to the strengths.
SGD, however, is one of the slower
algorithms we could use
because it possibly has to go through many
iterations until it learns a good fit.
Plus one to the weaknesses now.
Remember all the unobserved user item
interactions we had in the prior tables?
Well, unfortunately, user item
interaction data tends to be very sparse,
especially for problems with a large
number of users and columns.
So we want an algorithm that can
handle this lack of observations.
Unfortunately, SGD has
a hard time handling these.
So that is another con for
SGD, bringing us to a total of
two strengths and two weaknesses.
Another algorithm we can use is
alternating least squares, or ALS, which
alternatively solves U holding V constant,
and then solves for V holding U constant.
Let's look at the strengths and
weaknesses of this method now.
Well, unfortunately, as the name suggests,
this algorithm only works for
least squares problems.
So that is plus one for weaknesses.
However, luckily, for this particular
problem, we have a least squares loss
that we are trying to minimize,
so this is still a viable option.
Just like SGD,
ALS is a paralyzable algorithm.
Therefore, we can also scale out our
problem to handle much larger data
in a shorter amount of time.
Plus one to the strengths.
ALS is usually much faster
at convergence than SGD.
This makes sense because SGD is
a more of a generalist algorithm,
which gives it it's flexibility.
However, ALS is a specialist algorithm for
least squares problems,
which this is, so it is somewhat optimized
to solve these types of problems faster.
Another plus one for the strengths.
Lastly, unlike SGD, ALS or
a close variant can
easily handle unobserved interaction
pairs, which is great news because those
are usually extremely abundant
in our interaction matrix.
That's another strength for ALS, bringing
us to a total of three strengths and
only one weakness.
Now, exactly what happens to
the unobserved interaction pairs?
Let's look at our earlier
interaction matrix,
specifically, the implicit
feedback version.
As you can see, we've replaced
the check marks with 1s instead.
So how do the different algorithms treat
the missing interaction pairs data?
One simple way to solve this is to
perform the singular value decomposition,
as we did in the previous course for
latent semantic analysis.
This matrix factorization method,
however, requires all real numbers
in the matrix it is decomposing.
Therefore, the unobserved
pairs are given values of 0.
You might think this is not significant,
but it greatly changed what the data
means, because we were essentially
making a large assumption and
imputing zeros wherever data was missing.
This can lead to poor performance
in making recommendations.
What else can we try instead?
Using matrix factorization for
collaborative filtering such as ALS,
we just ignore the missing values.
Notice that in the last formula,
we were minimizing.
We are only summing
the observed instances.
This deals in a great fix, but
with a minor tweak, we can obtain
something that usually works very well.
What if instead of merely setting all
unobserved pairs to 0, or ignoring them
completely, we assigned a weight for
those interaction pairs that are missing?
We can think of this as not giving it
an absolutely certain negative score, but
instead as a low confidence score.
This is called weighted alternating
least squares, or WALS for short.
Notice that in the modified equation,
we have the ALS term on the left and
a new term on the right that
weights the unobserved entries.
This usually provides much
better recommendations and
is the algorithm we will now focus on.
Now it's time to test your knowledge about
the ways unobserved pairs are handled
by different algorithms.
There are many ways to handle unobserved
user-interaction matrix pairs.
Blank explicitly sets all
missing values to zero.
Blank simply ignores missing values.
Blank uses weights instead of zeros that
can be thought of as representing blank.
Choose the answers that
best fill in the blanks.
The correct answer is B.
In singular value decomposition, or SVD,
we explicitly set all
machine values to zero.
This could be problematic because we
are making a very large assumption and
imputing data that could
have meaning when,
in fact, there was no data there,
which can throw off our predictions.
The matrix factorization of
a collaborative filtering algorithm,
alternating least squares or ALS,
simply ignores missing values.
Weighted alternating least squares, or
WALS, uses weights instead of zeros,
which can be thought of as
representing low confidence.
WALS provides some of the best
recommendation performance compared to
these other methods, and
is what we will focus on using for
collaborative filtering.