Now that we've had the overview,
let's take a deeper dive into each of the
two neural networks used for the YouTube
video recommendation system, starting
with the candidate generation network.
Just as we did with our design lab and
neural network lab, hybrid models require
intelligently assembling many other
machine learning models into a pipeline.
These use multiple datasets and
model types to help get
the best recommendations.
The first step for candidate generation
is see the item embeddings for
instance from a trained WALS model.
We then find the last 10
videos watched by the user and
use the embeddings to get their
vectors within embedding space.
Next, we average the embeddings
of those 10 videos, so we'll have
a resultant single embedding that is the
average along each embedding dimension.
This becomes the watch vector,
which will be one of the features
to our deep neural network.
We would do the same thing
with past search queries.
Collaborative filtering for
next search term is a collaborative
filtering model that is similar to
the user history based collaborative
filter we talked about earlier.
Essentially, this is like doing to
word to vec on pairs of search terms.
We will find an average search in Benin
and this will become our search vector.
Another input feature to
our deep neural network.
We also should add any knowledge
we have about the user.
Location is important so
you just conceive localised videos and
also because of language.
Gender may be important because there are
differences in preference based on that.
All of these are features added as
inputs to our deep neural network.
We also should add example age, because we
don't want to over emphasis older videos.
Why do we care about this?
Well, older videos have more likes and
more user interactions in general.
You want the model to learn to account for
the fact that older videos are more likely
to have been watched or searched for.
Hence, the need to add
example age as an input.
Remember, this is example age,
not user age.
These are all a subset of the many
features that feed into our candidate
generation neural network.
Next, we want to train a DNN Classifier.
Now, why would we want this model type?
When you think of a DNN Classifier's
output, it becomes pretty obvious.
The output will be a probability
that this video will be watched.
So taking the top n of these
videos is probably what we want.
These come out of a soft max for training,
but there are two other considerations.
There's also a benefit to
finding the closest users and
generating those candidates as well.
This is the way that
viral videos are created,
videos that a lot of people
like us are watching.
Therefore, we can treat the last but
one layer, or
the layer right before
softmax as a user embedding.
This is also a benefit to
finding videos related
content wise to the video
you are currently watching.
Therefore, we can use the output of
the DNN Classifier as video vectors.
This compounded with the last
relayer as the user embeddings
generates candidates during serving, so
nearest neighbors consist of neighboring
users and neighboring videos.
We now know the magic behind YouTube's
candidate generation neural network, so
let's see what we've learned.
During training of the candidate
generation network,
what output layer should we be using, and
what should we be predicting with it?
The correct answer is E.
We are trying to generate candidate
videos to send onto the ranking network,
half of our hybrid recommendation system.
Therefore, by using a Softmax, we can
get probabilities of which video will be
watched, and
we can then take the highest ones and
send those as our candidate
videos to the ranking network.