Using neural networks to combine all the advantages and eliminate
the disadvantages of the three broad types of recommendation systems is very powerful.
We were able to eliminate or at least mitigate the disadvantages of
each broad recommendation system approach
and use full advantage of their individual strengths.
These hybrid models fortunately don't use
any fancy new system and just build off of what we already have.
However, to get the full power to them,
we should provide as much data as possible from
many different sources and connect all these models together into an ML pipeline.
We put all this together ourselves in a hybrid neural network lab.
We learned about how context factors into our experiences with
items such as what our mood was at the time like our stress level,
who else we experience things with like our family,
where we experience things that matter from the everyday locations to the truly amazing,
how time plays a factor in our experience such as the difference in seasons,
or if we are experiencing things during special occasions,
wrapped up with the emotion, excitement, and expectations.
We learn how to take this context and use it with
the three main approaches of context-aware recommendation systems,
contextual pre-filtering, post-filtering, and modeling.
Lastly, we learned about some of the inner workings of
the YouTube video hybrid recommendation system and saw how
two different neural networks harnessing enormous amounts of
data can create some very powerful recommendations to delight its users.
In the next module,
we will see how we can productionize and automate much of the necessary pipeline using
the greater Google Cloud Platform ecosystem to make
our hybrid neural network recommendation system even better.