It's time to do a wrap up of
all the topics we've covered so
far in this course.
In this course, you learned about
the rapid growth and high resolution image
data available and the types of
applications that it can be applied to.
We covered a number of
business applications,
like how Airbus detects
clouds versus snow cover and
how Q Pie makes better baby food
by classifying bad potatoes.
We also looked at some of the latest
medical image classification models,
like the one helping prevent blindness by
detecting diabetic retinopathy earlier and
assisting physicians with diagnosis.
Since it's usually good to
start with a simpler approach
first you build image classifiers using
linear and deep neural network models.
You saw that while linear models
train quickly, there was room for
improvement and accuracy.
We turned our attention to
deep neural networks and
saw how they could handle more complex
classification tasks quite well.
We ran into trouble when we
attempted to train at scale
in a reasonable amount of time and
without memorizing our training data.
We then followed the rise of convolutional
neural networks, with a critical milestone
being the Alex Stent Model,
winning the Image Net competition in 2012.
The critical improvement is that using
CNNs allows our model to share weights
thus reducing the number of weights.
That also allows our ML
model to be more tolerant,
a slight variations in the images because
of pattern recognition through kernels and
filtered output layers.
We covered the fundamental shift of
having the model itself figure out what
filters to learn and
apply instead of you, the data scientist,
specifying what patterns look for
up front.
This front-loaded set of convolutional and
pulling layers allow CNNs to
achieve high accuracy,
be more tolerant of image distortions, and
reduce high dimensionality to eventually
feed into our DNN for classification.
Next we dealt with data scarcity and
improved our model with augmentation,
batch normalization,
and transfer learning.
You practiced augmenting your dataset by
implying transformations like rotation,
zoom, crop, blur, and more.
You then delve into transfer learning
where you use the front part of the CNN,
which was already great at
extracting features from images, and
transferred it over to a newly appended,
fully connected DNN.
We then discuss how to implement
state of the art image models,
with tensor processing units, or TPUs,
which have a significant performance
advantage over traditional CPU processing.
We then saw how batch
normalization has the effect
of enhancing gradients at later iterations
which allows you to train faster.
Lastly we reviewed how
you can use pre built ML
models like Google Cloud's Vision API or
AutoML platforms,
which are powered by
some of the latest and
greatest image classification model
behind the scenes like NASnet.
In your lab, you created a JSON request
to Google Clouds Vision API and
got back labels associated
with your image.
Then, you experimented with AutoML, which
is a codeless solution that allows you to
train and deploy a vision model offered
as part of Google AutoML's offering.
AutoML uses a combination
of transfer learning
using some of Google's best models and
neural architecture search.
All you have to do is upload your
models into Cloud Storage and
the product does the rest.
That's a rap for Image Classification
Models, we'll see you in the next course
on Sequence Models for our time series and
natural language processing.
See you there.