One of the key decisions you'll need
to make about your production ML system
concerns training.
Here's a riddle.
How is physics unlike fashion?
If we assume that science is about
discovering relationships that already
exist in the world,
then the answer is that physics is
constant whereas fashion isn't.
To see some proof, just look at
some old pictures of yourself.
Now, you might be asking,
why is this relevant?
The reason it's relevant is that when
making decisions about training,
you have to decide whether the phenomenon
you're modelling is more like physics or
like fashion.
When training your model, there
are two paradigms, static training and
dynamic training.
In static training, we do what we
did in the last specialization.
We gather our data, we partition it,
we train our model, and then we deploy it.
In dynamic training,
we do this repeatedly as more data arrive.
This leads to the fundamental
trade-off between static and dynamic.
Static is simpler to build and
test, but likely to become stale.
Whereas dynamic is harder to build and
test, but will adapt to changes.
And the tendency to become or not become
stale is what I was alluding to earlier
when I contrasted physics and fashion.
If the relationship you're trying to model
is one that is constant, like physics,
then a statically trained
model may be sufficient.
If on the other hand the relationship
your trying to model is like fashion,
then the dynamically trained
model might be more appropriate.
Part of the reason the dynamic
is harder to build and
test is our that new data may
have all sorts of bugs in it.
And that's something we'll talk about more
deeply in a later course on designing
adoptable ML systems.
Can you think of other reasons why
the engineering might be harder?
The reason is that we need more
monitoring, model rollback, and
data quarantine capabilities.
Let's test our understanding
with some new use cases.
Take a moment to read
the problem column and
think about which sort of training
style would be appropriate.
First use case concerns spam detection.
And the question you
should ask yourself is,
how fresh does spam detection need to be?
You could do this as static, but spammers
are a crafty and determined bunch.
They will likely figure out ways of
passing whatever filter you impose within
short order.
So dynamic is likely to be
more effective over time.
What about Android Voice-to-Text?
Note that this question has some subtlety.
For a global model,
training offline is probably fine.
But if you want to personalize
the voice recognition,
you may need to do something online,
or at least different, on the phone.
So this could be static or dynamic
depending on whether you want global or
personalized transcription.
What about ad conversion rate?
The interesting subtlety here is that
conversion may come in very late.
For example, if I'm shopping for
a car online, I'm unlikely to buy for
a very long time.
What does dynamic training
look like in this setting?
One system I know uses dynamic training,
but then regularly goes back at different
intervals to catch up on new conversion
data that has arrived for the past.
In practice, most of the time,
you'll need to do dynamic, but
you might start with static
because it's simpler.
This is a reference architecture for
static training.
And it's the same thing we've done so far,
where the models are trained once and
then pushed to ML engine.
Now, for dynamic training, there are three
potential architectures to explore,
Cloud functions, App Engine,
or Cloud Dataflow.
Here's the general architecture for
dynamic training using Cloud functions.
A new data file appears in Cloud storage
and then the Cloud function is launched.
The Cloud function starts
Cloud MLE training job, and
then the Cloud ML engine
writes out a new model.
Now, let's look at a specific
architecture that uses Cloud Composer.
Here is a more sophisticated
dynamic training architecture that
you'll see a demo of in the next
module on Data Ingestion.
Here we have an orchestration layer with
Cloud Composer which has cloud functions
that trigger cloud data flow
processing jobs on new data
based on new data files being
dropped into Google Cloud Storage.
That data is then processed and
stored and then fed into Cloud ML Engine.
This diagram illustrates
a user making a web request,
perhaps from a dashboard to AppEngine.
Then a Cloud ML Engine
training job is launched, and
the Cloud ML Engine job writes
a new model to Cloud storage.
And then finally, the statistics of
the training job are displayed to the user
when the job is complete.
It's also possible that the dataflow
pipeline is invoking the model for
predictions.
And we'll build a pipeline in module 3,
Designing Adaptable ML Systems,
that does just that.