Now that we have created our training and
testing data sets,
let's train a model on Cloud ML Engine.
Among many reasons it allows you to train
on large amounts of data with plentiful
compute, and perhaps even training
models in parallel as we will be doing.
Training in the cloud also allows you to
take advantage of hyperparameter tuning.
So how do you actually
train a model on the cloud?
Well, the key is packaging
up your model logic,
and then submitting that job to ML Engine.
So that's what we are really
going to be focusing on in this lab.
And then once we're finished with this lab
we're going to move on to the next step
where we will be ready to serve
predictions from the model that we're
about to train the end users.
But for right now, let's focus on
training our model using Cloud ML Engine.
So you can go ahead and
go to the fifth lab,
which is going to be 5_train,
and open up that notebook.
In this notebook we're going to specify
the bucket and project and region,
as we normally have been doing.
And we want to set this as
environmental variables.
This command will copy over the CSV files
from the cloud chain
demos babyweight example.
From the babyweight folder in case you
are unable to complete the prior lab.
Regardless, you should have
a list of pre-processing
CSV files that we
completed in the prior lab.
And what do these contain?
Well if I run this we can do gsutil ls,
and we can look at a couple of examples.
So these are going to be eval and
train.csv files across
the entire data set.
So this means we're now going to be able
to train our model on a very large data
set, because we're going to
be using ML Engine.
So what did two labs ago was we
verify that our code will be
working on a subset of the data.
We verified that the code
was able to learn and
that there are some signal on our data.
But now, let's package up this
TensorFlow code as a Python module which
would primarily involve adding a set
up.py file, and an init.py file.
Those are two requirements for
Python packages.
And then we'll also add a test.py
file which will be responsible for
parsing user inputs.
Once we package up our Python code,
we can then submit the code,
the training code to Cloud ML Engine.
And the code in the model.py will be
the same as the TensorFlow notebook.
So let's take a look at more
detail at the structure.
So if I go back to the root
directory that we've been looking
at there's a folder called babyweight.
The babyweight contains a couple examples.
It contains a package info and
a setup.cfg.
These are options metadata files, but
what is required is the setup.py.
If we look at this, this contains
essentially instructions on how to install
our Python package, this is
a requirement for all python packages.
Or the meat of this package is
though is in the trainer directory.
There's three files here.
There's the empty init.py file which is
just a requirement for Python packages.
There's the model.py code,
which is what we had already written in
the prior labs that contains
all the model logic.
And there's the task.py which
contains argument parsing logic so
we can have command line
arguments that are input,
that are used to execute
the model that we've created.
So, for example by open up the task.py
file, we can look at what's going on.
We're going to input argparse library, and
you're going to see a lot of this code
is going to be argument parsing, right?
So we're adding all sorts of arguments,
training examples,
batch size, number of embeddings,
neuro network size.
So the bulk of this code really is
going to be parsing out user arguments,
and then we're going to call our
model code train and evaluate.
Where is that located?
Well, that's located in the model.py file.
So if we open up model.py,
this is going to contain
the code that we've
already worked with and
we developed locally.
So returning to the notebook,
we can look at a high level, and
all of the functions that
we defined in the model.py.
Read dataset, get wide and
deep, train and evaluate,
these all look familiar because
we created them in a prior lab.
So now that we've packaged
up our Python code,
let's test it out locally before
we turn our model Cloud ML Engine.
So first,
let's remove babyweight_trained in case
there is a model that start from scratch.
Then we'll set our Python
path to babyweight.
This will allow us to execute all of our
code from within the babyweight package.
Then, we will call the trainer package and
the task,
that's the task.py module and
we'll specify the bucket,
which we've already set above
a certain environmental variable.
The output directory.
What is the output directory?
The output directory is where we're
going to store our trained model.
This is will be really important when want
to serve our model because we need to
actually push this training model to
the cloud, but that will be for later.
We need to specify job directory,
we'll just set it to temp because it's
not utilized but we need to provide it.
And we need to specify how we're
going to read our input data,
how many training examples we have and
how many steps.
So these are all arguments that
we specified in our task.py file.
So you can go ahead and call this, and
this will take a couple minutes as you
run locally, if you run it locally.
So after waiting about 30 seconds or so,
we trained our model just
using one training step.
Of course, this is not predictive model,
we don't actually expect to make
operations with this, because it's
trained with such little data.
But what we can do is we can verify our
code logic, our monologic is working.
So let's scroll down and we can see
our model has successfully trained.
And now let's write some test data,
or rather let's write some example
features that we can use to make
a prediction using the Predict API.
So we'll use the writefile magic.
What this allows us to do is
write a file called inputs.json,
and write out JSON files that are going to
contain the features that we talked about.
So, in this case is male will be true,
we'll specify mother's age etc.
This is just made up data that we're
going to use to test our model.
We want to specify the model location.
And remember, this was the output
dir that we specified above.
And then we can use this gcloud
ml-engine local predict.
This is a local function that you
should just use for testing but
what thi will do is allow us to ensure
that our serving function is working okay,
and that our model logic
is functioning properly.
So we can do that,
point it to the model location,
import it to this example
inputs that we've made.
So we did a run input.json.
And I'll run gcloud ml-engine
local predict and for
each one of these keys we'll
get some sort of prediction.
Of course we have a negative prediction
for babyweight but this was expected.
We didn't actually train a model,
we trained it for one step so
we shouldn't expect these
predictions to be accurate.
All right, with that, now we've shown
the code works well in standalone mode.
So, now let's run it on Cloud ML Engine.
And because this is on the entire
data set it will take a long time,
depending on which scale to use, in this
case the training took about an hour.
Let's go over the job quickly and
then we'll show
how you can monitor the job
using the Cloud console.
So in this case we specified
the output directory.
This is going to be where
we want to save our model.
We want to specify the job name.
We're just going to add a date time
stamp so we can make it a unique name.
We're going to remove the output
directory if it exists.
That way we can start from scratch.
And, then we're going to run gcloud
ml-engine jobs submit training.
So this is the code to submit
a training job to ml-engine.
We want to say the job name, the region
where we're going to train the model.
What to actually execute
which is that trainer.task.
Remember the task.py file
we'll call our model logic and
the model.py file, but
we want to call the task file first.
We need to specify where
the package path is.
That's babyweight/trainer.
The job directory which we'll just use
in this case the same as our $OUTDIR.
A staging bucket,
which will be our bucket.
And then we'll specify the scale tier and
the TensorFlow runtime version.
One important thing I really want
to call out is this dash dash that
you see separates arguments
that are specific to ML Engine.
Versus argument that are specific to
our file as defined in our task.py.
So, these one's are all
the arguments that we created in
our task.py where the arguments
before are specific to ML Engine.
So we're going to use the bucket,
we're going to use our own bucket.
The output directory that we specified,
and now we're going to train for
200,000 examples.
So go ahead and run that.
Once we submit our job,
we can monitor it in several ways.
One way is we can use TensorBoard in
a manner that we did perform earlier.
Another approach that we can do is we
can monitor it using the Cloud console.
So what you can do is you can
go to console.cloud.google.com.
And then in this case,
let's search for ML Engine at the top.
We can do ML Engine jobs.
In this case, I've already ran the
babyweight job, and so it's complete but
we can click there and we can actually
see logs for our model in real time.
All right, let's go back.
So what we specified above was we
specified command line parameters that we
wanted to use for our program.
These parameters though,
there's an optimal set of parameters that
will give us the best result, right?
Chances are the first parameter
we chose are not going to
necessarily the best model.
A better approach is to use hyperparameter
tuning which allows us to try a range or
a set of different parameters to
figure out what are the optimal
hyperparameters that result and
the best model results.
And the way that you do so
is by creating hyperparam.yaml file.
For this file, there's a couple
things that we need to specify.
We need to specify most importantly
what are the parameters that we want to
optimize over?
So in this case we want to specify,
we want to optimize over the batch size,
the number of embeddings for
the wide and deep model for.
Specifically the deep part of the model,
the neural network size that we're
going to use,
the dimensions of our network.
So those are the three perimeters
that we're going to use to optimize.
We specify the scaleTier that we want to
use, what is the metric we're interested
in and this case it's going to
be root means square to.
We want to minimize our messy.
We specify how many trials
we're going to run it for, and
then also how many trials we're
going to run in parallel.
In this case we have 5.
Why might you want to
set more ParallelTrials.
Well, it will go faster, right?
When we run more jobs in
parallel we'll finish earlier.
But if you set too many parallel trials
you won't be able to learn from your prior
trials as it won't become
a sequential learning process.
So it's important to not set
too many max ParallelTrials,
otherwise you're just going to perform for
min naive grid search.
And what we can do is we
can specify a range for
the different parameters we're interested
in a range that we want to search for.
So for batch size we want to say,
a minimum value could be 8 and
maximum value would be 512.
All right, so we can run this, and
we'll create a hyperparam.yaml file.
And now, we're going to do
exactly what we performed above,
except there's going to
be a key difference.
We specify the config file.
The config file is the hyperparam.yaml
that we've built above, and
this will automatically submit
a hyper parameter training job for us.
So if we go back to our jobs in ML Engine,
you can look at the different types.
So you'll notice that I already
submitted a hyperparameter training job.
So let's go ahead and look at it.
So the hyperparameter logs contain
a couple points of interest.
Number 1,
it contains the information that we just
specified in our hyperparameter.yaml.
We want to optimize batch_size,
number of embeds, etc.
But perhaps the most important thing
that it contains is the actual output
of your results of your
hyperparametering job.
So in this case, out of all the 20 trials
it sorts it by order of performance.
So in this case, the best performing
model had a neural network size of 511,
a batch size of 511 and
the number of embeds into 7.
And the objective value was 1.09.
After that, we got a pretty similar result
using the slightly different setting.
So generally you want to look
at some of these top, if not,
usually the top parameter combination and
use that for your model going forward.
So finally, let's repeat our
training using the tuned parameters.
So in this case we're not
specifying a hyperparam.yaml file.
We're just going to use a set
of batch-sized embeddings and
neural network size
that we learned before.
This was tuned with
a slightly different setup.
So the parameters are different
than what we just talked about.
But this is where you should put
the parameters that you tune during your
hyperparameter tuning,
and this will be the model that
we'll want to use going forward.
Great, that's it for
training on ML Engine.
We actually trained several different
models, and in the case of hyperparameter
tuning, we trained several
different models in parallel.
We were able to use tensor
board to visualize our results.
And we also got a console.cloud.google.com
to look at the actual logs of our files.
This is really useful for training
hyperparameter change jobs where you want
to see what are the optimal parameters
that came out of model training.
Next, we're going to use Google,
we're going to use ML Engine to
surf predictions for a model.
our model is currently stored in
a Google Cloud Storage bucket, so
we're going to point ML Engine to our
trained model which was specified by
that model file and then we're going to
use that to serve predictions.
So let's talk about that going forward.
Now that you've used ML Engine
to train your model,
let's talk about the next step of
actually serving our model to end users.