As we discussed in the last module,
variable length sequences are common
placed in many sequence use cases,
but cannot be elegantly handled by the
types of models we looked at previously.
Our options, which include cutting and
padding as well as bagging,
either throw away information or
else are inefficient.
What we need is a model that is designed
to handle variable-length sequences.
Thankfully such a model exists and
it's called a recurrent neural net.
In this module,
we'll introduce recurrent neural networks,
explain how they address the variable
length sequence problem.
Explain how our traditional optimization
procedure applies RNNs, and
review the limits of what RNNs can and
can't represent.
Recurrent neural networks, or
RNNs, handle variable-length
sequences by recasting the problem of
representing an entire variable-length
sequence to representing a single
event given what has come before.
To gain some intuition for
why this is not just reasonable but
actually consistent with what you do
every day, let's take a little detour.
Think about when someone's speaking
to you and gets interrupted.
For example, if I were to say,
dogs are my favorite animals,
I love how they wag their,
and then I stopped, you'd probably have a
good idea of what I was going to say next.
The fact that you do, that you aren't
incapacitated by an incomplete sentence,
suggests that you've built up
a representation of what I've said so far.
And in this case,
you can use that representation
to predict what might come next.
RNNs are designed to
function in a similar way.
Instead of accepting a fixed size input
representing an entire sequence like DNNs
do, they accept a fixed size
representation of a particular event along
with a fixed size representation
of what they've seen previously.
By a particular event, I'm referring
to a day, in a sequence of days, or
a word in a sequence of words.
So for example, in order to pass in
the sequence, dogs wag their to a DNN,
we'd probably either concatenate our
representations for each word or
else bag those representations
to get the fixed size input.
Of course, saying that we have
a representation of the important parts of
what we've seen previously,
which is what RNNs require,
trivializes the most interesting and
complicated part of RNNs.
Because if we knew how to represent what
we've seen previously regardless of how
long it was, we wouldn't have
this problem in the first place.
We could try to tackle this
problem using feature engineering.
But in deep learning,
we have another option,
letting the model engineer its
own features during optimization.
And that's exactly what RNNs do.
In that sense, much the way that
CNNs learn filters as they train and
can evolve those filters across images and
ultimately learn how to be
good feature image extractors.
RNNs scan their input
layer across sequences and
learn how to extract information from
a given event in order to make use
of it at a later point in the sequence.
And ultimately become good
sequence feature extractors.
There are two key ideas
in the RNN architecture.
First, RNNs learn to
predict the output but
they also learn how to compact
all of the previous inputs.
And secondly,
the input to an RNN is a concatenation of
the original stateless input and
this new hidden state.
This idea of a persistent hidden state
that is learned from ordered inputs is
what distinguishes an RNN from linear and
deep neural networks.
In a DNN, the hidden state is
not updated during prediction.
In RNN, it is.
In the next section we'll talk about
how these aspects of RNNs allow them to
remember what they've seen previously.