Welcome to the last module of the image classification course.
Now that you have built your own image classifiers using linear,
DNN and CNN models with TensorFlow,
it's time to experiment with pre-built image models.
In most cases, you will want to try these before
investing your time in developing custom TensorFlow code for a model.
This module, we'll start with a brief overview of
the different pre-built models available from Google.
You will also see examples of popular business applications of each.
You'll start by reviewing the spectrum of ML options on Google Cloud platform,
with a focus on the pre-built and pre-trained models for image classification.
With Cloud ML Vision API,
you will classify images without even having to provide a training images dataset.
The API relies on Google's pre-trained model you can use directly from browser.
Next, you will move on to AutoML service,
which allows you to get state of the art image classification results from
models trained with your own custom labels and your own image dataset.
You will see a demo of the service and then
compare AutoML and the Vision API in the upcoming lab.