In the first module of this course on
production machine learning systems,
we discussed many of the things that
the system should be able to do.
And the components that take
responsibility for doing these things.
We also discussed important decisions
that system architects will have to make.
For training, whether we do dynamic
training or static training,
and the same for inference.
The answers to these questions
drives the architecture.
And finally, you got to practice
designing and architecture from scratch.
In the second module, we talked about
how to bring your data to the cloud.
We covered transfer methods like gsutil to
directly ingest data into
Google Cloud Storage.
The transfer appliance that we shipped to
you to fill up and you should be back.
We talked about cloud
storage transfer service,
which is a great way to transfer
data between regions at Google.
And the BigQuery transfer service that
automates loading data into BigQuery
from a variety of sources.
In module three, we talked about change,
how it affects machine learning systems,
and what we can do to mitigate,
to reduce those effects.
And in module four, we talked about how
to squeeze the most performance out
of the machine learning system by choosing
the right hardware removing bottles.
And in module five, we talked the high
level about the technology behind hybrid
systems, which might run on the Cloud,
on the Edge or on-premises.
And that's a wrap for
Production Machine Learning Systems.
We'll see you in the next course
on Image Classifications Models.
Where we will delve into convolutional
networks, transfer learning and
tensor processing units.
Thank you.