My name is Katherine Zhao.
I am an AI engineer at Google Cloud.
You have learned many use cases,
that can be solved using sequence models,
like time series prediction and
text classification.
In both those cases, the label or
what has to be predicted,
is just a single value.
What if you need the model
to output not just
the temperature tomorrow, or
the source of the newspaper article?
What if you need the model to
output a full sequence as well?
This is the kind of problem
you face if you want to
build a machine learning model
to summarize an article.
Now the model has to generate
an entire paragraph, how do you do it?
In this module,
we will focus on a sequence to sequence
model called encoder-decoder
network to solve
this use case,
such as machine translation,
text summarization, and
question answering.
Let's say we want to input
an English sentence,
the cat ate the mouse,
and translate it into
the French sentence [FOREIGN].
How can we train a neural
network to input a sequence
of English sentence and
output a sequence of French sentence.
Well, here's something that we could do.
First, let's have a network that
we're going to call it the encoder.
It is built as an un-wrote
recurrent neural network, or RNN.
This could also be LSDM or GRU.
Then we feed the English
sentence one word at a time.
After ingesting the inputs into the RNN,
we all put a vector that
represents the input sentence.
After that, we compute another network.
Now we're going to call it the decoder.
The decoder takes the outputs from
the encoder network as its input.
Then it can be trained to output
the translation one word at a time,
until eventually it reaches
the end token of the sentence.
That is how the decoder stops.
One of the most remarkable result in deep
learning shows that this model works,
given enough pairs of English and
French sentences.
If we're trained a model to
input an English sentence,
and output the corresponding
French translation,
this model actually works decently well.
A problem that does not have an easy
standard solution is the softmax layer.
If we want to compute
word probabilities over
the entire English vocabulary, let's say,
100,000 English words, we need a softmax
layer that outputs a vector
of 100,000 elements.
And then each element typically
comes with a range of 500 ways.
That's 50 million ways to
predict one word, ouch!
For predictions, we don't have a choice.
But for training, the only thing that
we're interested in is the gradients.
Many techniques have been devised to
compute gradients in a cheap,
approximate way.
TensorFlow has implemented a couple of
techniques to speed up this process.
For example,
we can use sampled_softmax_loss
method to compute and
return the training loss.
Now the translation model,
a string, let's try out.
How does the model predict a translation?
We have that the English
sentence into the encoder.
The outputs of the encoder
becomes the inputs
of the first RN cell of the decoder.
The input of the cell is some arbitrary
go token that marks
the beginning of the sentence.
For the predictions, we can simply
call the embedding_lookup method
to look up IDs in a list
of embedding tensors.
Then we enroll the RN inputs using
the method called dynamic_rnn.
Y is going to be a dense layer.
With the softmax, we can get
the conditional probability of
each word in the vocabulary.
But how to get the actual predicted
words from those probabilities?
The first idea is to do greedy search,
which generates the first
word just by picking up
whatever is the most likely first word,
according to its probability.
After picking the first word,
we then pick whatever
is the second word that seems
most likely and continue.
Problem of this approach is very obvious
as it does not produce
the best translation.
So what should we do about it?
The neural network gives us at
each time step of the decoding
the conditional probability of the next
word by knowing what came before.
Now, given a model predicting
conditional probability
of the next word, how can we
compute the most probable sequence?
This is a very well researched
problem in computer science.
It has applications in compression,
signal transmission, and here as well.
A few algorithms can be
used to solve this problem,
and the most widely used
one is called beam search.
Instead of picking only one
most likely word at each
time step in the decoder network and
then move on.
Like the greedy search does, beam search
can consider multiple
alternatives at a time.
TensorFlow has an implementation
called BeamSearchDecoder,
and we can simply use that for
our predictions.