Example here shows that sometimes,
the original sentence
may not perfectly align with
the translation at each time step.
In this example,
the first English word is black.
Well, the first French word is chat.
That means cat in English.
How could we train the model to
pay more attention to the word
cat instead of the word black
at the first time step?
In the translation model,
the intuition behind attention
network is that it allows
the new network to pay attention
to only part of the input sentence
while generating a translation.
Much like a human translator would do.
Now, let's formalize
the intuition into the exact
details of how we could
implement an attention network.
The attention network
could be something similar
to the blue mini neural
network on the left.
Before moving on,
let's define some notations.
Alpha represents the tension
weight at each time step.
H represents the hidden state
of encoder RN at each time step.
H subscript d represents the hidden
state of the decoder RN at each time step.
To train the attention network,
we will follow three steps.
First, we want the tension weights.
Alpha to depend on the current word
being translated in both languages.
So the mini network that
produces the tension
weights will taking into account both
the hidden states of the encoder RN and
the hidden state of the decoder
RN at times step heat.
This gives us our attention weight for
a given words of the input
English sentence for
each words of the output,
French sentences.
Then the tension vector,
alpha 1 times H1 plus alpha
2 times H2 plus, etc.
Gets combined with the hidden state of
the decoder RN at time step P to fine tune
the translation for current output word.
Lastly, the combined factor is
also used as an additional input in
the decoder RN at time step t plus 1.
We keep moving on by following these three
steps until reaching
the end of sentence token.
The inversion of the black
cat translation is
clearly visible in the attention diagram.
So is the fact that eight translates
as two words in French.
We can see the tension network staying
focused on the word eight for
two time steps.
It sounds like a lot of work, right?
But don't panic, there are high level APIs
available in TensorFlow that we can use.