In this specialization, you will learn how to do
machine learning at scale and how to build
specialized machine-learning models for images, sequences, and recommendations.
Hi I'm Lak, I lead the team that put together this specialization.
We start with a course that recaps the first specialization.
It involves building an end-to-end model from
data exploration all the way to deploying an ML model and getting predictions from it.
The second course is on building production machine learning models.
The considerations behind them, static training,
dynamic training, static inference,
dynamic inference, distributed TensorFlow.
TensorFlow processing units, when would you use what.
The third course is on building image models.
You will learn about convolutional neural networks and
build image classification models of various types.
The fourth course is on building sequence models.
These are the types of models used in
natural language problems like text classification and translation.
There can also be used for time series forecasting.
Although as we'll see in this course it's
often overkill and hard to train for this purpose.
Finally, we end the specialization with building real-world recommendation systems.
This brings together all the concepts that we will have
learned in both the previous specialization and in this one.
I'm excited to have you join me.